<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>main on My Cookbook</title>
    <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/tags/main/</link>
    <description>Recent content in main on My Cookbook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 16:06:11 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/tags/main/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tortillas ans Fajitas</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/tortillas-and-fajitas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/tortillas-and-fajitas/</guid>
      <description>Tortillas Ingredients (makes about a dozen tortillas, ~55g each)  450g AP flour 330ml warm water 4g salt (1 small teaspoon) 75g lard  or
 675g AP flour 495ml warm water 6g salt (1.5 small teaspoon) 100g lard  Recipe  Mix lard with flour, mix in salt Start mixing the warm water, don&amp;rsquo;t mix all of it in first. Add enough water so that sticky dough forms. Knead the dough for ~10 minutes, or until it&amp;rsquo;s smooth, supple, and is not sticky any more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fried Chicken Sandwich</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/fried-chicken-sandwich/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/fried-chicken-sandwich/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Chicken 1 tablespoon Diamond Crystal or 1¾ teaspoons Morton kosher salt
1 teaspoon light brown sugar
1 teaspoon baking powder
4 skin-on or skinless, boneless chicken thighs
Seasoned Mayonnaise 1 garlic clove, finely grated
2 tablespoons fresh lemon juice
½ cup mayonnaise
2 tablespoons finely chopped chives
½ teaspoon celery seeds
½ teaspoon freshly ground black pepper
Kosher salt
Assembly  1½ cups all-purpose flour ⅓ cup cornstarch 1 tablespoon garlic powder 1 tablespoon onion powder 1 tablespoon paprika 2 teaspoons cayenne pepper 2 tablespoons Diamond Crystal or 3½ teaspoons Morton kosher salt, plus more 1 large egg, beaten to blend 1 cup buttermilk 2 tablespoons bourbon (optional) 3 tablespoons hot sauce (such as Frank’s); plus more for serving (optional) Peanut or vegetable oil (for frying; about 8 cups) 4 seeded soft hamburger buns 3 tablespoons unsalted butter, melted Bread-and-Butter Pickles (for serving), plus 1 tablespoon brine 4 cups thinly sliced iceberg lettuce Freshly ground black pepper  Recipe Chicken Step 1 Mix salt, sugar, and baking powder in a small bowl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paneer Tikka Masala</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/paneer-tikka-masala/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/paneer-tikka-masala/</guid>
      <description>Tikka  2 tbsp yoghurt 1 tbsp chickpea flour 1 tsp paprika powder 1.5 tsp coriander powder 0.5 tsp masala powder 0.25 tsp turmeric powder less than 0.5 tsp salt   Mix everything well, then coat paneer, bell pepper and onion pieces well. Put it in the refrigerator for 20 minutes. Then roast them on oil or butter until they become golden brown.  Masala gravy  2 tbsp oil 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spicy Chicken Stir-Fry</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/spicy-chicken-stir-fry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/spicy-chicken-stir-fry/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 tsp. plus ¼ cup soy sauce 2½ tsp. cornstarch, divided 1½ tsp. sugar, divided ½ tsp. chilli powder (optional) ½ tsp. kosher salt, plus more 1 lb. skinless, boneless chicken thighs 1 tbsp. unseasoned rice vinegar 1 tbsp. oyster sauce 4 garlic cloves 1 2&amp;quot; piece ginger 1 bell pepper 1 onion 1 carrot 4 scallions ⅓ cup vegetable oil ¾ cup roasted, salted peanuts Rice (for serving; optional)  Recipe Whisk together 2 tsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Steak</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/steak/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/steak/</guid>
      <description>Season steak with salt and pepper, and let it sit at room temp for 30 minutes. Preheat the oven to 110 C, and bake the steak for around 45 minutes, or until the middle registers at 50 C. Heat 1 tbsp oil on high heat, and sear the steak on both sides for 2 minutes. Add 2-3 tbsp butter, 1 clove of garlic and a sprig of rosemary, and baste both sides for 90 seconds.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
