<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>My Cookbook on My Cookbook </title>
      <generator uri="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</generator>
    <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    
    <updated>Mon, 20 May 2024 16:06:11 &#43;0100</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pasta alla Norma</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/pasta-alla-norma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 16:06:11 &#43;0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/pasta-alla-norma/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1½ pounds eggplant Olive oil as needed (at least ½ cup) Salt and pepper 1 tablespoon chopped garlic 3 or 4 dried chiles 1½ pounds tomatoes, chopped (canned are fine; about 1 can) 1 teaspoon good dried oregano, or 1 tablespoon fresh 1 pound long pasta ½ cup chopped parsley or basil ½ cup grated ricotta salata (or in a pinch, pecorino Romano)  Recipe Step 1
Slice the eggplant about ½ inch thick.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banana muffin</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/banana-muffin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 16:06:11 &#43;0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/banana-muffin/</guid>
      <description>1 1/2 cups (190g) all purpose flour 2/3 cup (132g) sugar 1 1/2 teaspoons baking powder 1/4 teaspoon salt 1 cup mashed ripe bananas (about 2 large) 1 large egg 110g unsalted butter, melted 80ml milk 3/4 cup semisweet chocolate chips  Step 1
Preheat oven to 350°F. Line twelve 1/3-cup muffin cups with foil muffin liners. Mix flour, sugar, baking powder and salt in large bowl. Mix mashed bananas, egg, melted butter and milk in medium bowl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rakott krumpli</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/rakott-krumpli/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 16:06:11 &#43;0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/rakott-krumpli/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1100 g potatoes 550 ml sour cream salt 6 large eggs 200 g kelbasa, optionally bacon 100 g cheese  Recipe Parboil potatoes for ~15 minutes.
Boil eggs for ~15 minutes, cut in circles.
Stir-fry the kelbasa.
Butter a baking pan, and coat it with breadcrumbs.
Mix sour cream with some salt.
Layer potatoes, eggs, kelbasa, sour cream.
On the final layer, put potatoes, and top with grated cheese.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate Cake</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/chocolate-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 16:06:11 &#43;0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/chocolate-cake/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients (Makes one 23cm cake)
 ¾ cup vegetable oil, plus more for pan 1⅓ cups all-purpose flour 1¼ cups granulated sugar 1¾ tsp. baking powder ¼ tsp. baking soda 1½ tsp. kosher salt, divided ½ cup unsweetened cocoa powder 2 large eggs 1 cup milk 1¾ tsp. vanilla extract, divided 4 oz. semisweet chocolate chips or coarsely chopped chocolate bars (do not exceed 64% cacao) ½ cup heavy cream 4 oz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spaghetti Puttanesca</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/spaghetti-puttanesca/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 16:06:11 &#43;0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/spaghetti-puttanesca/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 /4 cup extra-virgin olive oil 4 large garlic cloves, finely chopped 1 28.2-ounce can peeled tomatoes in puree with basil 1/2 cup Kalamata olives, halved, pitted 3 anchovy fillets, chopped 1 1/2 tablespoons drained capers 1 teaspoon dried oregano 1/2 teaspoon dried crushed red pepper 3/4 pound spaghetti 2 tablespoons chopped fresh Italian parsley Grated Parmesan cheese  Recipe Step 1
Heat oil in large pot over medium heat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Green bean casserole</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/green-bean-casserole/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2023 16:06:11 &#43;0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/green-bean-casserole/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients (8 servings)
 1kg green beans Kosher salt 2 Tbsp. extra-virgin olive oil, divided 1 lb. crimini mushrooms, sliced, divided 6 Tbsp. unsalted butter, divided 4 large sprigs thyme, divided 2 Tbsp. all-purpose flour 300ml cups whole milk 240ml cup heavy cream 4 garlic cloves, finely grated ½ cup grated Parmesan Freshly ground black pepper ¾ cup French’s fried onions  Recipe  Preheat oven to 190 C Cook beans to half tender in salted water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eggplant parmesan</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/eggplant-parmesan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 16:06:11 &#43;0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/eggplant-parmesan/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1kg eggplant 1 tsp salt, plus more to taste 1/4 cup plus 1 tablespoon extra virgin olive oil, divided, plus more to oil the sheet pans 2 cloves garlic, minced 2 (28-ounce or 800g) cans whole peeled tomatoes (preferably San Marzano) diced, reserving the juices, or crushed tomatoes 1/2 cup finely chopped fresh basil, packed Kosher salt Freshly ground black pepper, to taste 1 1/2 to 2 cups breadcrumbs 1 1/4 cups shredded Parmesan cheese, divided 1 cup all-purpose flour 4 large eggs, beaten (more if needed) 700g pounds fresh mozzarella cheese, sliced into 1/4-inch slices  23cm x 33cm casserole</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plum dumpling</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/plum-dumpling/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 08:06:11 &#43;0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/plum-dumpling/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Dough  1.5 kg potato 1 tsp salt 1 egg 300-500g AP flour  Plums  1 kg plums 3 tbsp granulated sugar 1 tsp cinnamon  Breadcrumbs  3 tbsp oil 200g breadcrumbs  Recipe  Peel and chop potatoes, boil until tender Mash the potatoes, and let it rest until completely cooled Mix mashed potatoes, egg, salt and flour, work into smooth dough Partially halve the plums and remove the seeds Fry the breadcrumbs in the oil Shape dumplings, boil them, for 3-4 more minutes from the point when they come to the surface of the water Roll dumplings into breadcrumbs Serve with confectionar&amp;rsquo;s sugar  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banana bread</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/banana-bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2023 16:06:11 &#43;0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/banana-bread/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Makes one 21cm x 12cm loaf
 1½ cups (188 g) all-purpose flour 1¼ tsp. baking soda ¾ tsp. Diamond Crystal or ½ tsp. Morton kosher salt 1 cup (200 g; packed) dark brown sugar ⅓ cup mascarpone, plain whole-milk Greek yogurt, or sour cream 4 Tbsp. unsalted butter, room temperature 2 large eggs 4 large very ripe bananas, peeled, mashed (about 1½ cups) ½ cup chopped bittersweet or semisweet chocolate (optional) ½ cup chopped raw walnuts (optional)  Recipe Preheat oven to 175C°.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baba Ganoush (eggplant dip)</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/baba-ganoush/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2023 16:06:11 &#43;0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/baba-ganoush/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 to 2 globe eggplants (totaling 2 pounds or 900g) 3 tablespoons extra virgin olive oil 2 to 3 tablespoons roasted tahini (sesame paste) 1 to 2 garlic cloves (more or less depending on how garlicky you want your baba ghanoush to be), finely chopped 1/2 teaspoon ground cumin Juice of 1 lemon (about 2 1/2 tablespoons) Salt and cayenne pepper to taste 1 tablespoon chopped parsley  Recipe Cut eggplants in half, poke them with a fork.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pancit Bihon Guisado</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/pancit-bihon-guisado/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2023 06:06:11 &#43;0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/pancit-bihon-guisado/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 onion, chopped 1 carrot, julienned 4 cloves garlic, crushed 300g chicken breast, thighs, or pork ribs 1/2 tsp salt 3 tbsp soy sauce 3 tbsp oyster sauce 3 cups of water 250g rice vermicelli handful of chopped cabbage or lettuce  Recipe  Heat oil in a wok. Saute carrots, then remove from wok and put aside. Saute onions on high heat for a minute. Add garlic, cook for a couple of seconds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strawberry shortcake</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/strawberry-shortcake/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 16:06:11 &#43;0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/strawberry-shortcake/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 cups all-purpose flour, plus more for surface 1½ tsp. baking powder ¼ tsp. baking soda ½ cup plus 1 tsp. sugar, divided 1½ tsp. kosher salt, plus more 1 lemon ½ cup (1 stick) cold unsalted butter 1 cup sour cream, divided 2 cups heavy cream, divided 1½ lb. strawberries 1 tsp. vanilla extract  Recipe Place a rack in center of oven; preheat to 400°. Line a rimmed baking sheet with parchment paper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Csirkepaprikás</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/csirkepaprikas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 16:06:11 &#43;0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/csirkepaprikas/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Base  2 cloves garlic 2 red onions 4 chicken thighs 2 pieces paprika 2 tbsp paprika powder 3 tbsp fat or oil 2 tomatoes water 3 pinches of salt  Roux  200g sour cream 1 tbsp flour  Recipe  Chop the garlic, onions, paprika, tomatoes. Cut the whole thighs in half. Saute the paprika, then the onions, and the garlic. Turn down the heat, and add the paprika powder, tomatoes, 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bolognese sauce</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/bolognese/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 16:06:11 &#43;0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/bolognese/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 medium onion, chopped 1 celery stalk, chopped 1 small carrot, peeled, chopped 3 Tbsp. extra-virgin olive oil 1 lb. ground beef chuck (20% fat), patted dry Kosher salt 3 oz. thinly sliced pancetta, finely chopped 1 cup dry white wine ⅓ cup tomato paste 1 bay leaf Pinch of finely grated nutmeg 2 cups (or more) homemade chicken stock or low-sodium chicken broth 1 cup whole milk 1 lb.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fasírt</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/fasirt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 16:06:11 &#43;0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/fasirt/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  500g ground pork 1 medium sized red onion, chopped 3 gloves garlic 2 eggs 2 buns 1 tsp salt black pepper 0.5 tsp paprika breadcrumbs  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>

