<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>My Cookbook on My Cookbook </title>
      <generator uri="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</generator>
    <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    
    <updated>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 16:06:11 &#43;0100</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hong Shao Rou (红烧肉)</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/hong-shao-rou/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 16:06:11 &#43;0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/hong-shao-rou/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Pork belly  500g pork belly piece of ginger scallions 2 tbsp cooking wine  Stir frying  1 tbsp sugar 3 cloves of garlic 0.5 tsp Sichuan peppercorns 1 small piece of cinnamon 1/8 of a nutmeg 1 small star anise 1 small piece of bay leaf 1 piece of dry chili ginger  Braising  1.5 cup water (boiling, important!) scallion 2 tbsp soy sauce 2 tbsp cooking wine (for braising) 1/8 tsp salt  Recipe Sear pork belly skin side down until browned.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chinese stir-fried green beans</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/chinese-stir-fried-green-beans/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 14:06:11 &#43;0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/chinese-stir-fried-green-beans/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  400g green beans 2 tsp oil 1 tbsp dark soy sauce 1 tbsp cooking wine 2 tsp minced garlic 2 tsp grated ginger 1/2 tsp sugar 1/2 tsp sesame oil 1/4 tsp salt 1/4 tsp red pepper flakes (optional) Garnish: sesame seeds  Recipe Combine sauce ingredients.
Dry-fry beans in a little oil for 10 minutes, until tender crisp and charred.
Pour sauce into skillet, sauté for a couple of minutes until thickened and the beans are coated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leek potato cream soup</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/leek-potato-cream-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 16:06:11 &#43;0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/leek-potato-cream-soup/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 tablespoons unsalted butter 1 medium onion 2 cloves of garlic 2 large leeks, white and pale green parts only, rinsed and roughly chopped 1 quart homemade or store-bought low-sodium chicken stock 2 medium russet potatoes, peeled and cut into quarters (about 3/4 pound) 1 bay leaf Kosher salt and freshly ground black pepper 1 cup milk 1/2 cup heavy cream 1/2 teaspoon freshly ground nutmeg Sliced chives or scallions, for serving  Recipe Sautee onions, garlic, and then leeks, until soft.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yorkshire pudding</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/yorkshire-pudding/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 16:06:11 &#43;0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/yorkshire-pudding/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  140g AP flour 4 eggs 200ml milk oil  Recipe Mix batter, and rest in fridge for a couple of hours, or overnight.
Preheat oven to 220 C, drizzle a little oil in holes of muffin pan.
Put pan in the oven to heat it up.
Pour batter into muffin holes evenly, bake for 20-25 minutes until the puddings puffed up and are brown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pumpkin cream soup</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/pumpkin-cream-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 16:06:11 &#43;0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/pumpkin-cream-soup/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2kg pumpkins 4 tablespoons butter 2 cups medium yellow onions, chopped, about 2 cups 3 clove garlic cloves, minced 2 to 3 teaspoons smoked paprika, more or less to taste 1/2 teaspoon ground cumin 1 pinch cayenne pepper 1 large tart green apple peeled, cored, chopped (about 2 cups) 4 cups chicken broth 1 cup water 1 teaspoon fresh thyme or 1/2 teaspoon dried thyme 1/4 teaspoon ground sage 1 cup milk 1/2 cup cream Kosher salt and freshly ground black pepper, to taste Handful of toasted pepitas (shelled pumpkin seeds) for garnish  Recipe Bake pumpkin at 180 C for 45-60 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ceasar salad</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/ceasar-salad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 16:06:11 &#43;0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/ceasar-salad/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients CAESAR DRESSING  6 anchovy fillets packed in oil, drained 1 small garlic clove Kosher salt 2 large egg yolks 2 Tbsp. fresh lemon juice, plus more ¾ tsp. Dijon mustard 2 Tbsp. extra-virgin olive oil ½ cup vegetable oil 3 Tbsp. finely grated Parmesan Freshly ground black pepper  CROUTONS  3 cups torn 1&amp;quot; pieces country bread, with crusts 3 Tbsp. extra-virgin olive oil Kosher salt, freshly ground black pepper  ASSEMBLY  3 romaine hearts, leaves separated Parmesan, for serving  Recipe CAESAR DRESSING Step 1 Chop together 6 anchovy fillets packed in oil, drained, 1 small garlic clove, and a pinch of kosher salt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pasta alla Norma</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/pasta-alla-norma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 16:06:11 &#43;0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/pasta-alla-norma/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1½ pounds eggplant Olive oil as needed (at least ½ cup) Salt and pepper 1 tablespoon chopped garlic 3 or 4 dried chiles 1½ pounds tomatoes, chopped (canned are fine; about 1 can) 1 teaspoon good dried oregano, or 1 tablespoon fresh 1 pound long pasta ½ cup chopped parsley or basil ½ cup grated ricotta salata (or in a pinch, pecorino Romano)  Recipe Step 1
Slice the eggplant about ½ inch thick.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banana muffin</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/banana-muffin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 16:06:11 &#43;0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/banana-muffin/</guid>
      <description>1 1/2 cups (190g) all purpose flour 2/3 cup (132g) sugar 1 1/2 teaspoons baking powder 1/4 teaspoon salt 1 cup mashed ripe bananas (about 2 large) 1 large egg 110g unsalted butter, melted 80ml milk 3/4 cup semisweet chocolate chips  Step 1
Preheat oven to 350°F. Line twelve 1/3-cup muffin cups with foil muffin liners. Mix flour, sugar, baking powder and salt in large bowl. Mix mashed bananas, egg, melted butter and milk in medium bowl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rakott krumpli</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/rakott-krumpli/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 16:06:11 &#43;0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/rakott-krumpli/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1100 g potatoes 550 ml sour cream salt 6 large eggs 200 g kelbasa, optionally bacon 100 g cheese  Recipe Parboil potatoes for ~15 minutes.
Boil eggs for ~15 minutes, cut in circles.
Stir-fry the kelbasa.
Butter a baking pan, and coat it with breadcrumbs.
Mix sour cream with some salt.
Layer potatoes, eggs, kelbasa, sour cream.
On the final layer, put potatoes, and top with grated cheese.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate Cake</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/chocolate-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 16:06:11 &#43;0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/chocolate-cake/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients (Makes one 23cm cake)
 ¾ cup vegetable oil, plus more for pan 1⅓ cups all-purpose flour 1¼ cups granulated sugar 1¾ tsp. baking powder ¼ tsp. baking soda 1½ tsp. kosher salt, divided ½ cup unsweetened cocoa powder 2 large eggs 1 cup milk 1¾ tsp. vanilla extract, divided 4 oz. semisweet chocolate chips or coarsely chopped chocolate bars (do not exceed 64% cacao) ½ cup heavy cream 4 oz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spaghetti Puttanesca</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/spaghetti-puttanesca/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 16:06:11 &#43;0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/spaghetti-puttanesca/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 /4 cup extra-virgin olive oil 4 large garlic cloves, finely chopped 1 28.2-ounce can peeled tomatoes in puree with basil 1/2 cup Kalamata olives, halved, pitted 3 anchovy fillets, chopped 1 1/2 tablespoons drained capers 1 teaspoon dried oregano 1/2 teaspoon dried crushed red pepper 3/4 pound spaghetti 2 tablespoons chopped fresh Italian parsley Grated Parmesan cheese  Recipe Step 1
Heat oil in large pot over medium heat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Green bean casserole</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/green-bean-casserole/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2023 16:06:11 &#43;0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/green-bean-casserole/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients (8 servings)
 1kg green beans Kosher salt 2 Tbsp. extra-virgin olive oil, divided 1 lb. crimini mushrooms, sliced, divided 6 Tbsp. unsalted butter, divided 4 large sprigs thyme, divided 2 Tbsp. all-purpose flour 300ml cups whole milk 240ml cup heavy cream 4 garlic cloves, finely grated ½ cup grated Parmesan Freshly ground black pepper ¾ cup French’s fried onions  Recipe  Preheat oven to 190 C Cook beans to half tender in salted water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eggplant parmesan</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/eggplant-parmesan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 16:06:11 &#43;0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/eggplant-parmesan/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1kg eggplant 1 tsp salt, plus more to taste 1/4 cup plus 1 tablespoon extra virgin olive oil, divided, plus more to oil the sheet pans 2 cloves garlic, minced 2 (28-ounce or 800g) cans whole peeled tomatoes (preferably San Marzano) diced, reserving the juices, or crushed tomatoes 1/2 cup finely chopped fresh basil, packed Kosher salt Freshly ground black pepper, to taste 1 1/2 to 2 cups breadcrumbs 1 1/4 cups shredded Parmesan cheese, divided 1 cup all-purpose flour 4 large eggs, beaten (more if needed) 700g pounds fresh mozzarella cheese, sliced into 1/4-inch slices  23cm x 33cm casserole</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plum dumpling</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/plum-dumpling/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 08:06:11 &#43;0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/plum-dumpling/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Dough  1.5 kg potato 1 tsp salt 1 egg 300-500g AP flour  Plums  1 kg plums 3 tbsp granulated sugar 1 tsp cinnamon  Breadcrumbs  3 tbsp oil 200g breadcrumbs  Recipe  Peel and chop potatoes, boil until tender Mash the potatoes, and let it rest until completely cooled Mix mashed potatoes, egg, salt and flour, work into smooth dough Partially halve the plums and remove the seeds Fry the breadcrumbs in the oil Shape dumplings, boil them, for 3-4 more minutes from the point when they come to the surface of the water Roll dumplings into breadcrumbs Serve with confectionar&amp;rsquo;s sugar  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banana bread</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/banana-bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2023 16:06:11 &#43;0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/banana-bread/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Makes one 21cm x 12cm loaf
 1½ cups (188 g) all-purpose flour 1¼ tsp. baking soda ¾ tsp. Diamond Crystal or ½ tsp. Morton kosher salt 1 cup (200 g; packed) dark brown sugar ⅓ cup mascarpone, plain whole-milk Greek yogurt, or sour cream 4 Tbsp. unsalted butter, room temperature 2 large eggs 4 large very ripe bananas, peeled, mashed (about 1½ cups) ½ cup chopped bittersweet or semisweet chocolate (optional) ½ cup chopped raw walnuts (optional)  Recipe Preheat oven to 175C°.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>

