<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>My Cookbook on My Cookbook </title>
      <generator uri="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</generator>
    <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    
    <updated>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 16:06:11 &#43;0100</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tortillas ans Fajitas</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/tortillas-and-fajitas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 16:06:11 &#43;0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/tortillas-and-fajitas/</guid>
      <description>Tortillas Ingredients (makes about a dozen tortillas, ~55g each)  450g AP flour 380ml warm water 4g salt 90g lard  Recipe  Mix lard with flour, mix in salt Start mixing the warm water, don&amp;rsquo;t mix all of it in first. Add enough water so that sticky dough forms. Knead the dough for ~10 minutes, or until it&amp;rsquo;s smooth, supple, and is not sticky any more. Cover, let rest for 30 minutes Form balls, ~55g each, and bake on hot skillet  Chicken fajitas Ingredients Chicken  1 1/4 to 1 1/2 pounds skinless, boneless chicken breasts Salt 2 tablespoons canola, safflower, peanut, or extra virgin olive oil 1 large onion, sliced lengthwise (root to tip) into 1/4-inch strips 3 bell peppers various colors, sliced into 1/4-inch strips  For the marinade:  2 tablespoons lime juice 3 tablespoons extra virgin olive oil 1 garlic clove, minced 1/2 teaspoon salt 1/2 teaspoon ground cumin 1/2 teaspoon chili powder 1/2 jalapeño, seeded and minced 1/4 cup chopped cilantro  Salsa  2-3 large, ripe tomatoes 1 medium red onion 1 clove of garlic Scallions (optional) Salt Pepper  For serving:  8 to 12 flour tortillas Salsa Sliced avocado Sour cream Thinly sliced iceberg lettuce dressed lightly with salt and cider vinegar  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple pie</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/apple-pie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 16:06:11 &#43;0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/apple-pie/</guid>
      <description>3 pounds (1360g) good cooking apples such as Granny Smith, Jonagold, Golden Delicious, Fuji, or Braeburn (about 6 to 8 apples, depending on the size of your apples and the size of your pie dish) 1 tablespoon lemon juice or apple cider vinegar (to toss with the sliced apples so they don&amp;rsquo;t brown as you slice them) 1/2 cup to 2/3 cup sugar, depending on how sweet you like your pie 3 tablespoons all-purpose flour for thickening 1/2 teaspoon cinnamon 1/4 teaspoon ground allspice 1/4 teaspoon ground nutmeg 1 tablespoon brandy (Optional.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate chip cookie</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/chocolate-chip-cookie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 16:06:11 &#43;0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/chocolate-chip-cookie/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1½ cups (200 g) all-purpose flour (spooning into measuring cups, then leveling) 1¼ tsp. (4 g) Diamond Crystal or ¾ tsp. (4 g) Morton kosher salt ¾ tsp. (4 g) baking soda ¾ cup (1½ sticks; 169 g) unsalted butter, divided 1 cup (200 g) (packed) dark brown sugar ¼ cup (50 g) granulated sugar 1 large egg 2 large egg yolks 2 tsp. vanilla extract 6 oz. (170 g) bittersweet chocolate (60%–70% cacao), coarsely chopped, or semisweet chocolate chips  Recipe Place racks in upper and lower thirds of oven; preheat to 375°.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fried Chicken Sandwich</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/fried-chicken-sandwich/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 16:06:11 &#43;0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/fried-chicken-sandwich/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Chicken 1 tablespoon Diamond Crystal or 1¾ teaspoons Morton kosher salt
1 teaspoon light brown sugar
1 teaspoon baking powder
4 skin-on or skinless, boneless chicken thighs
SEASONED MAYONNAISE 1 garlic clove, finely grated
2 tablespoons fresh lemon juice
½ cup mayonnaise
2 tablespoons finely chopped chives
½ teaspoon celery seeds
½ teaspoon freshly ground black pepper
Kosher salt
ASSEMBLY 1½ cups all-purpose flour
⅓ cup cornstarch
1 tablespoon garlic powder</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mashed Potatoes</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/mashed-potatoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 16:06:11 &#43;0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/mashed-potatoes/</guid>
      <description> Cook the peeled, chopped potatoes (1.5kg) in salty water, 15-20 minutes. Mash the potatoes. Melt ~100g butter. Stir it into the potatoes. Heat up 1 cup of cream, and add aromatics (2-3 cloves of garlic) Stir the cream into the the potatoes in small batches.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Milk bread</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/milk-bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 16:06:11 &#43;0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/milk-bread/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 packet of dry yeast (about 2 tsp.) 360 g bread flour 17 g (1.5 Tbsp.) sugar 7 g (0.5 Tbsp.) kosher salt 17 g (1 Tbsp. plus 0.5 tsp.) unsalted butter, room temperature, plus more for bowl  Recipe  Whisk yeast and 0.25 cup warm water (about 90°) in a small bowl. Let sit until foamy, about 5 minutes. Mix flour, sugar, and salt, and gradually add yeast mixture, and 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paneer Tikka Masala</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/paneer-tikka-masala/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 16:06:11 &#43;0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/paneer-tikka-masala/</guid>
      <description>Tikka  2 tbsp yoghurt 1 tbsp chickpea flour 1 tsp paprika powder 1.5 tsp coriander powder 0.25 tsp turmeric powder less than 0.5 tsp salt   Mix everything well, then coat paneer, bell pepper and onion pieces well. Put it in the refrigerator for 20 minutes. Then roast them on oil or butter until they become golden brown.  Masala gravy  2 tbsp oil 0.5 tsp cumin seeds 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sinclair Potato Rolls</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/sinclair-potato-rolls/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 16:06:11 &#43;0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/sinclair-potato-rolls/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients (makes 6 potato rolls)
 All-Purpose Flour, 290g Whole Milk, 100g Yukon Gold Potatoes, cooked and riced, 67g Potato Cooking Liquid, 24g Butter, 29g Eggs, 28g (half an egg) White Sugar, 24g Sea Salt, 7g Instant Yeast, 2g, or 5g Cake Yeast  Recipe  Mix dry ingredients Fold in the wet ingredients and mix, knead until dough forms. Let it rest covered in bowl for 20 minutes. Knead for a couple of minutes, form into ball, let it rise covered in bowl for 1 hour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sourdough bread</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/sourdough-bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 16:06:11 &#43;0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/sourdough-bread/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  350 grams bread flour (preferably organic) 90 grams whole wheat flour (preferably organic and stone-ground) 350 grams 90°F/32°C filtered water 90 grams ripe sourdough starter (100% hydration) 9 grams kosher salt or fine sea salt white rice flour, for dusting  Example schedule Day one  8:30 AM – autolyse (mix flours and water). allow mixture to rest, covered, at 80°F/26°C for 1 hour, or as long as 2 hours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spicy Chicken Stir-Fry</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/spicy-chicken-stir-fry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 16:06:11 &#43;0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/spicy-chicken-stir-fry/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 tsp. plus ¼ cup soy sauce 2½ tsp. cornstarch, divided 1½ tsp. sugar, divided ½ tsp. kosher salt, plus more 1 lb. skinless, boneless chicken thighs 2 Tbsp. unseasoned rice vinegar 4 garlic cloves 1 2&amp;quot; piece ginger 6 scallions ⅓ cup vegetable oil ¾ cup roasted, salted peanuts Rice (for serving; optional)  Recipe Whisk together 2 tsp. soy sauce, 1½ tsp. cornstarch, ½ tsp. sugar, and ½ tsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Steak</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/steak/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 16:06:11 &#43;0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/steak/</guid>
      <description>Season steak with salt and pepper, and let it sit at room temp for 30 minutes. Preheat the oven to 110 C, and bake the steak for around 45 minutes, or until the middle registers at 50 C. Heat 1 tbsp oil on high heat, and sear the steak on both sides for 2 minutes. Add 2-3 tbsp butter, 1 clove of garlic and a sprig of rosemary, and baste both sides for 90 seconds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2014 13:49:44 &#43;0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/search/</guid>
      <description>      $(document).ready(function() { $(&#39;#tipue_search_input&#39;).tipuesearch({ &#39;mode&#39; : &#39;json&#39;, &#39;show&#39;: 10, &#39;newWindow&#39;: true, &#39;wholeWords&#39;: false }); });    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>

