<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>My Cookbook on My Cookbook </title>
      <generator uri="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</generator>
    <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    
    <updated>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 08:06:11 &#43;0100</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plum dumpling</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/plum-dumpling/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 08:06:11 &#43;0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/plum-dumpling/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Dough  1.5 kg potato 1 tsp salt 1 egg 300-500g AP flour  Plums  1 kg plums 3 tbsp granulated sugar 1 tsp cinnamon  Breadcrumbs  3 tbsp oil 200g breadcrumbs  Recipe  Peel and chop potatoes, boil until tender Mash the potatoes, and let it rest until completely cooled Mix mashed potatoes, egg, salt and flour, work into smooth dough Partially halve the plums and remove the seeds Fry the breadcrumbs in the oil Shape dumplings, boil them, for 3-4 more minutes from the point when they come to the surface of the water Roll dumplings into breadcrumbs Serve with confectionar&amp;rsquo;s sugar  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banana bread</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/banana-bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2023 16:06:11 &#43;0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/banana-bread/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Makes one 21cm x 12cm loaf
 1½ cups (188 g) all-purpose flour 1¼ tsp. baking soda ¾ tsp. Diamond Crystal or ½ tsp. Morton kosher salt 1 cup (200 g; packed) dark brown sugar ⅓ cup mascarpone, plain whole-milk Greek yogurt, or sour cream 4 Tbsp. unsalted butter, room temperature 2 large eggs 4 large very ripe bananas, peeled, mashed (about 1½ cups) ½ cup chopped bittersweet or semisweet chocolate (optional) ½ cup chopped raw walnuts (optional)  Recipe Preheat oven to 175C°.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pancit Bihon Guisado</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/pancit-bihon-guisado/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2023 06:06:11 &#43;0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/pancit-bihon-guisado/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 onion, chopped 1 carrot, julienned 4 cloves garlic, crushed 300g chicken breast, thighs, or pork ribs 1/2 tsp salt 3 tbsp soy sauce 3 tbsp oyster sauce 3 cups of water 250g rice vermicelli handful of chopped cabbage or lettuce  Recipe  Heat oil in a wok. Saute carrots, then remove from wok and put aside. Saute onions on high heat for a minute. Add garlic, cook for a couple of seconds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strawberry shortcake</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/strawberry-shortcake/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 16:06:11 &#43;0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/strawberry-shortcake/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 cups all-purpose flour, plus more for surface 1½ tsp. baking powder ¼ tsp. baking soda ½ cup plus 1 tsp. sugar, divided 1½ tsp. kosher salt, plus more 1 lemon ½ cup (1 stick) cold unsalted butter 1 cup sour cream, divided 2 cups heavy cream, divided 1½ lb. strawberries 1 tsp. vanilla extract  Recipe Place a rack in center of oven; preheat to 400°. Line a rimmed baking sheet with parchment paper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Csirkepaprikás</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/csirkepaprikas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 16:06:11 &#43;0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/csirkepaprikas/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Base  2 cloves garlic 2 red onions 4 chicken thighs 2 pieces paprika 2 tbsp paprika powder 3 tbsp fat or oil 2 tomatoes water 3 pinches of salt  Roux  200g sour cream 1 tbsp flour  Recipe  Chop the garlic, onions, paprika, tomatoes. Cut the whole thighs in half. Saute the paprika, then the onions, and the garlic. Turn down the heat, and add the paprika powder, tomatoes, 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bolognese sauce</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/bolognese/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 16:06:11 &#43;0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/bolognese/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 medium onion, chopped 1 celery stalk, chopped 1 small carrot, peeled, chopped 3 Tbsp. extra-virgin olive oil 1 lb. ground beef chuck (20% fat), patted dry Kosher salt 3 oz. thinly sliced pancetta, finely chopped 1 cup dry white wine ⅓ cup tomato paste 1 bay leaf Pinch of finely grated nutmeg 2 cups (or more) homemade chicken stock or low-sodium chicken broth 1 cup whole milk 1 lb.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fasírt</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/fasirt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 16:06:11 &#43;0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/fasirt/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  500g ground pork 1 medium sized red onion, chopped 3 gloves garlic 2 eggs 2 buns 1 tsp salt black pepper 0.5 tsp paprika breadcrumbs  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greek salad</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/greek-salad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 16:06:11 &#43;0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/greek-salad/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Salad  4 tomatoes 1 cucumber 4 small red onions 20 dkg olives 125 g feta cheese  Dressing  4 tbsp olive oil 1.5 tsp lemon juice 1 tsp dried basil  Recipe Mix the dressing ingredients in a small bowl, chill in fridge for an hour.
Chop the tomatoes, cucumber and onions, mix them in a bowl.
Chop the feta into small cubes, mix it with the rest of the salad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pizza dough</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/pizza-dough/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 16:06:11 &#43;0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/pizza-dough/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  153 grams 00 flour (1 cup plus 1 tablespoon) 153 grams all-purpose flour (1 cup plus 1 tablespoon and 2 teaspoons) 8 grams fine sea salt (1 teaspoon) 2 grams active dry yeast (¾ teaspoon) 4 grams extra-virgin olive oil (1 teaspoon)  Recipe Step 1 In a large mixing bowl, combine flours and salt.
Step 2 In a small mixing bowl, stir together 200 grams (a little less than 1 cup) lukewarm tap water, the yeast and the olive oil, then pour it into flour mixture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Potato salad with mayonaise</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/potato-salad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 16:06:11 &#43;0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/potato-salad/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 kg potato 5 dl sour cream 3 red onions, chopped or finely sliced 2 dl mayonaise 1 tbsp mustard 0.5 tsp black pepper 0.5 tsp sugar juice of 0.5 lemon salt  Recipe Boil potatoes in salted water for 15-20 minutes.
Cut them into circles.
For the sauce, mix the mayo with the sour cream, mustard, salt, sugar, pepper and lemon juice.
Put the potatoes in a bowl, mix it with the onions and the sauce.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carrot cake</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/carrot-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 08:06:11 &#43;0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/carrot-cake/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Cake  Nonstick vegetable oil spray 1 cup chopped walnuts 1 pound carrots, peeled, coarsely grated 1 cup buttermilk, room temperature 2½ cups all-purpose flour 2 teaspoons ground cinnamon 2 teaspoons ground ginger ½ teaspoon freshly grated nutmeg 2 teaspoons baking powder 1½ teaspoons kosher salt ¾ teaspoon baking soda 4 large eggs, room temperature 1 cup granulated sugar ¾ cup (packed) dark brown sugar 2 teaspoons vanilla extract ¾ cup vegetable oil  Frosting and assembly  12 ounces cream cheese, room temperature ¾ cup (1½ sticks) unsalted butter, room temperature 1 teaspoon vanilla extract Generous pinch of kosher salt 4 cups powdered sugar Candied Carrot Coins (optional)  Recipe Cake Step 1</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yoghurt cake</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/yoghurt-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 08:01:11 &#43;0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/yoghurt-cake/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  Butter, for greasing the pan 4 large eggs, separated, at room temperature ½ cup/100 grams granulated sugar 3 tablespoons all-purpose flour 1⅔ cups/400 grams whole-milk Greek yogurt 1 lemon, zested and juiced Pinch of salt (optional)  Recipe Step 1
Heat oven to 350 degrees and butter an 8- or 9-inch springform pan.
Step 2
Using an electric hand mixer or a standing electric mixer fitted with the whisk attachment, beat egg whites on medium-low until the mixture looks frothy, 1 to 2 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicken Tikka Masala</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/chicken-tikka-masala/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 09:06:11 &#43;0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/chicken-tikka-masala/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Chicken tikka  900 grams boneless, skinless chicken thighs 1 tablespoon kosher salt 1 tablespoon red chili powder 6 garlic cloves, peeled and mashed into a paste 1 (1-inch) piece ginger, peeled and mashed into a paste 2 lemons, juiced 1 cup|225 grams plain yogurt ¼ cup|60 ml canola oil 1 tablespoon garam masala 2 teaspoons ground turmeric 2 tablespoons unsalted butter, melted  Makhni gravy  1 pound|450 grams tomatoes, halved 1 garlic clove, peeled and mashed into a paste 1 (½-inch) piece ginger, peeled and mashed into a paste 1 teaspoon red chilli powder 1 small green chilli 1 cardamom pod 1 whole clove 15 grams cilantro with stems kosher salt, to taste ½ tablespoon unsalted butter ¼ cup|60ml heavy cream 2 tablespoons kasoori methi honey, to taste  Onion tomato masala  ¼ cup|60 ml canola oil ½ pound red onion, diced 2 garlic cloves, peeled and mashed into a paste 1 (¾-inch) piece ginger, peeled and mashed into a paste ½ teaspoon red chili powder ½ pound|225 grams tomatoes, diced ½ teaspoon garam masala kosher salt, to taste  Chicken tikka masala  3 tablespoons|150 grams ghee 3 teaspoons cumin seeds 8 whole dried red chiles 7 small garlic cloves, chopped 2 pounds|1 kg chicken tikka 2 teaspoons red chilli powder 1 ¼ cups onion tomato masala 1 ¼ cups makhni gravy 5 green chillies, thinly sliced ¼ cup|60 ml heavy cream 1 tablespoon unsalted butter 2 tablespoons kasoori methi 1 tablespoon garam masala kosher salt, to taste chopped cilantro, for garnish 1 (1-inch) piece ginger, peeled and julienned, for garnish steamed basmati rice, to serve  Directions Marinate the chicken: Place the chicken in a large bowl and toss with the salt, 1 teaspoon of the chili powder, half of the garlic paste, the lemon juice, and half of the ginger paste.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gnocchi</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/gnocchi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 06:06:11 &#43;0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/gnocchi/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients (4 servings)  500g potatoes 130g flour 0.5 tsp salt 1 egg  Recipe Bake potatoes in oven for 1 hour, until very tender. Or boil in water. Mash potatoes with fork, masher, or potato ricer. Mix together with the flour, salt and egg, mix and knead until the dough is smooth and not sticky. Cut and shape, then boil in salted water until comes to surface, ~3 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brioche</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/brioche/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 06:06:11 &#43;0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/brioche/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  T45 flour: 500g Salt: 9g Sugar: 70g Fresh yeast 15g Eggs: 150g (3 eggs) Milk: 150g Butter: 150g  Square pan: 27cm x 27cm
Recipe  Knead for 10 minutes without the butter Knead for 5 more minutes with the butter Pointing 30 min at room temperature and placing 12h at 4°c. Divide into 9 pieces Formatting Relaxation 10 min at 4°C Shaping, into 33cm snakes Braid them into 3 little loaves Primer: approximately 1h30min at 27°, in a turned off oven with a cup of hot water put under the pan Baking: 30 min at 150°C.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>

