<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on My Cookbook</title>
    <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on My Cookbook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 16:06:11 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hong Shao Rou (红烧肉)</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/hong-shao-rou/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/hong-shao-rou/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Pork belly  500g pork belly piece of ginger scallions 2 tbsp cooking wine  Stir frying  1 tbsp sugar 3 cloves of garlic 0.5 tsp Sichuan peppercorns 1 small piece of cinnamon 1/8 of a nutmeg 1 small star anise 1 small piece of bay leaf 1 piece of dry chili ginger  Braising  1.5 cup water (boiling, important!) scallion 2 tbsp soy sauce 2 tbsp cooking wine (for braising) 1/8 tsp salt  Recipe Sear pork belly skin side down until browned.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chinese stir-fried green beans</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/chinese-stir-fried-green-beans/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 14:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/chinese-stir-fried-green-beans/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  400g green beans 2 tsp oil 1 tbsp dark soy sauce 1 tbsp cooking wine 2 tsp minced garlic 2 tsp grated ginger 1/2 tsp sugar 1/2 tsp sesame oil 1/4 tsp salt 1/4 tsp red pepper flakes (optional) Garnish: sesame seeds  Recipe Combine sauce ingredients Dry-fry beans in a little oil for 10 minutes, until tender crisp and charred. Pour sauce into skillet, sauté for a couple of minutes until thickened and the beans are coated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leek potato cream soup</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/leek-potato-cream-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/leek-potato-cream-soup/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 tablespoons unsalted butter 1 medium onion 2 cloves of garlic 2 large leeks, white and pale green parts only, rinsed and roughly chopped 1 quart homemade or store-bought low-sodium chicken stock 2 medium russet potatoes, peeled and cut into quarters (about 3/4 pound) 1 bay leaf Kosher salt and freshly ground black pepper 1 cup milk 1/2 cup heavy cream 1/2 teaspoon freshly ground nutmeg Sliced chives or scallions, for serving  Recipe Sautee onions, garlic, and then leeks, until soft.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yorkshire pudding</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/yorkshire-pudding/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/yorkshire-pudding/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  140g AP flour 4 eggs 200ml milk oil  Recipe Mix batter, and rest in fridge for a couple of hours, or overnight.
Preheat oven to 220 C, drizzle a little oil in holes of muffin pan.
Put pan in the oven to heat it up.
Pour batter into muffin holes evenly, bake for 20-25 minutes until the puddings puffed up and are brown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pumpkin cream soup</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/pumpkin-cream-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/pumpkin-cream-soup/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2kg pumpkins 4 tablespoons butter 2 cups medium yellow onions, chopped, about 2 cups 3 clove garlic cloves, minced 2 to 3 teaspoons smoked paprika, more or less to taste 1/2 teaspoon ground cumin 1 pinch cayenne pepper 1 large tart green apple peeled, cored, chopped (about 2 cups) 4 cups chicken broth 1 cup water 1 teaspoon fresh thyme or 1/2 teaspoon dried thyme 1/4 teaspoon ground sage 1 cup milk 1/2 cup cream Kosher salt and freshly ground black pepper, to taste Handful of toasted pepitas (shelled pumpkin seeds) for garnish  Recipe Bake pumpkin at 180 C for 45-60 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ceasar salad</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/ceasar-salad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/ceasar-salad/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients CAESAR DRESSING  6 anchovy fillets packed in oil, drained 1 small garlic clove Kosher salt 2 large egg yolks 2 Tbsp. fresh lemon juice, plus more ¾ tsp. Dijon mustard 2 Tbsp. extra-virgin olive oil ½ cup vegetable oil 3 Tbsp. finely grated Parmesan Freshly ground black pepper  CROUTONS  3 cups torn 1&amp;quot; pieces country bread, with crusts 3 Tbsp. extra-virgin olive oil Kosher salt, freshly ground black pepper  ASSEMBLY  3 romaine hearts, leaves separated Parmesan, for serving  Recipe CAESAR DRESSING Step 1 Chop together 6 anchovy fillets packed in oil, drained, 1 small garlic clove, and a pinch of kosher salt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pasta alla Norma</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/pasta-alla-norma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/pasta-alla-norma/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1½ pounds eggplant Olive oil as needed (at least ½ cup) Salt and pepper 1 tablespoon chopped garlic 3 or 4 dried chiles 1½ pounds tomatoes, chopped (canned are fine; about 1 can) 1 teaspoon good dried oregano, or 1 tablespoon fresh 1 pound long pasta ½ cup chopped parsley or basil ½ cup grated ricotta salata (or in a pinch, pecorino Romano)  Recipe Step 1
Slice the eggplant about ½ inch thick.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banana muffin</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/banana-muffin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/banana-muffin/</guid>
      <description>1 1/2 cups (190g) all purpose flour 2/3 cup (132g) sugar 1 1/2 teaspoons baking powder 1/4 teaspoon salt 1 cup mashed ripe bananas (about 2 large) 1 large egg 110g unsalted butter, melted 80ml milk 3/4 cup semisweet chocolate chips  Step 1
Preheat oven to 350°F. Line twelve 1/3-cup muffin cups with foil muffin liners. Mix flour, sugar, baking powder and salt in large bowl. Mix mashed bananas, egg, melted butter and milk in medium bowl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rakott krumpli</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/rakott-krumpli/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/rakott-krumpli/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1100 g potatoes 550 ml sour cream salt 6 large eggs 200 g kelbasa, optionally bacon 100 g cheese  Recipe Parboil potatoes for ~15 minutes.
Boil eggs for ~15 minutes, cut in circles.
Stir-fry the kelbasa.
Butter a baking pan, and coat it with breadcrumbs.
Mix sour cream with some salt.
Layer potatoes, eggs, kelbasa, sour cream.
On the final layer, put potatoes, and top with grated cheese.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate Cake</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/chocolate-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/chocolate-cake/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients (Makes one 23cm cake)
 ¾ cup vegetable oil, plus more for pan 1⅓ cups all-purpose flour 1¼ cups granulated sugar 1¾ tsp. baking powder ¼ tsp. baking soda 1½ tsp. kosher salt, divided ½ cup unsweetened cocoa powder 2 large eggs 1 cup milk 1¾ tsp. vanilla extract, divided 4 oz. semisweet chocolate chips or coarsely chopped chocolate bars (do not exceed 64% cacao) ½ cup heavy cream 4 oz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spaghetti Puttanesca</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/spaghetti-puttanesca/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/spaghetti-puttanesca/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 /4 cup extra-virgin olive oil 4 large garlic cloves, finely chopped 1 28.2-ounce can peeled tomatoes in puree with basil 1/2 cup Kalamata olives, halved, pitted 3 anchovy fillets, chopped 1 1/2 tablespoons drained capers 1 teaspoon dried oregano 1/2 teaspoon dried crushed red pepper 3/4 pound spaghetti 2 tablespoons chopped fresh Italian parsley Grated Parmesan cheese  Recipe Step 1
Heat oil in large pot over medium heat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Green bean casserole</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/green-bean-casserole/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2023 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/green-bean-casserole/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients (8 servings)
 1kg green beans Kosher salt 2 Tbsp. extra-virgin olive oil, divided 1 lb. crimini mushrooms, sliced, divided 6 Tbsp. unsalted butter, divided 4 large sprigs thyme, divided 2 Tbsp. all-purpose flour 300ml cups whole milk 240ml cup heavy cream 4 garlic cloves, finely grated ½ cup grated Parmesan Freshly ground black pepper ¾ cup French’s fried onions  Recipe  Preheat oven to 190 C Cook beans to half tender in salted water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eggplant parmesan</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/eggplant-parmesan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/eggplant-parmesan/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1kg eggplant 1 tsp salt, plus more to taste 1/4 cup plus 1 tablespoon extra virgin olive oil, divided, plus more to oil the sheet pans 2 cloves garlic, minced 2 (28-ounce or 800g) cans whole peeled tomatoes (preferably San Marzano) diced, reserving the juices, or crushed tomatoes 1/2 cup finely chopped fresh basil, packed Kosher salt Freshly ground black pepper, to taste 1 1/2 to 2 cups breadcrumbs 1 1/4 cups shredded Parmesan cheese, divided 1 cup all-purpose flour 4 large eggs, beaten (more if needed) 700g pounds fresh mozzarella cheese, sliced into 1/4-inch slices  23cm x 33cm casserole</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plum dumpling</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/plum-dumpling/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 08:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/plum-dumpling/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Dough  1.5 kg potato 1 tsp salt 1 egg 300-500g AP flour  Plums  1 kg plums 3 tbsp granulated sugar 1 tsp cinnamon  Breadcrumbs  3 tbsp oil 200g breadcrumbs  Recipe  Peel and chop potatoes, boil until tender Mash the potatoes, and let it rest until completely cooled Mix mashed potatoes, egg, salt and flour, work into smooth dough Partially halve the plums and remove the seeds Fry the breadcrumbs in the oil Shape dumplings, boil them, for 3-4 more minutes from the point when they come to the surface of the water Roll dumplings into breadcrumbs Serve with confectionar&amp;rsquo;s sugar  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banana bread</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/banana-bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2023 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/banana-bread/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Makes one 21cm x 12cm loaf
 1½ cups (188 g) all-purpose flour 1¼ tsp. baking soda ¾ tsp. Diamond Crystal or ½ tsp. Morton kosher salt 1 cup (200 g; packed) dark brown sugar ⅓ cup mascarpone, plain whole-milk Greek yogurt, or sour cream 4 Tbsp. unsalted butter, room temperature 2 large eggs 4 large very ripe bananas, peeled, mashed (about 1½ cups) ½ cup chopped bittersweet or semisweet chocolate (optional) ½ cup chopped raw walnuts (optional)  Recipe Preheat oven to 175C°.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baba Ganoush (eggplant dip)</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/baba-ganoush/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2023 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/baba-ganoush/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 to 2 globe eggplants (totaling 2 pounds or 900g) 3 tablespoons extra virgin olive oil 2 to 3 tablespoons roasted tahini (sesame paste) 1 to 2 garlic cloves (more or less depending on how garlicky you want your baba ghanoush to be), finely chopped 1/2 teaspoon ground cumin Juice of 1 lemon (about 2 1/2 tablespoons) Salt and cayenne pepper to taste 1 tablespoon chopped parsley  Recipe Cut eggplants in half, poke them with a fork.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pancit Bihon Guisado</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/pancit-bihon-guisado/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2023 06:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/pancit-bihon-guisado/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 onion, chopped 1 carrot, julienned 4 cloves garlic, crushed 300g chicken breast, thighs, or pork ribs 1/2 tsp salt 3 tbsp soy sauce 3 tbsp oyster sauce 3 cups of water 250g rice vermicelli handful of chopped cabbage or lettuce  Recipe  Heat oil in a wok. Saute carrots, then remove from wok and put aside. Saute onions on high heat for a minute. Add garlic, cook for a couple of seconds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strawberry shortcake</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/strawberry-shortcake/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/strawberry-shortcake/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 cups all-purpose flour, plus more for surface 1½ tsp. baking powder ¼ tsp. baking soda ½ cup plus 1 tsp. sugar, divided 1½ tsp. kosher salt, plus more 1 lemon ½ cup (1 stick) cold unsalted butter 1 cup sour cream, divided 2 cups heavy cream, divided 1½ lb. strawberries 1 tsp. vanilla extract  Recipe Place a rack in center of oven; preheat to 400°. Line a rimmed baking sheet with parchment paper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Csirkepaprikás</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/csirkepaprikas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/csirkepaprikas/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Base  2 cloves garlic 2 red onions 4 chicken thighs 2 pieces paprika 2 tbsp paprika powder 3 tbsp fat or oil 2 tomatoes water 3 pinches of salt  Roux  200g sour cream 1 tbsp flour  Recipe  Chop the garlic, onions, paprika, tomatoes. Cut the whole thighs in half. Saute the paprika, then the onions, and the garlic. Turn down the heat, and add the paprika powder, tomatoes, 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bolognese sauce</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/bolognese/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/bolognese/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 medium onion, chopped 1 celery stalk, chopped 1 small carrot, peeled, chopped 3 Tbsp. extra-virgin olive oil 1 lb. ground beef chuck (20% fat), patted dry Kosher salt 3 oz. thinly sliced pancetta, finely chopped 1 cup dry white wine ⅓ cup tomato paste 1 bay leaf Pinch of finely grated nutmeg 2 cups (or more) homemade chicken stock or low-sodium chicken broth 1 cup whole milk 1 lb.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fasírt</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/fasirt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/fasirt/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  500g ground pork 1 medium sized red onion, chopped 3 gloves garlic 2 eggs 2 buns 1 tsp salt black pepper 0.5 tsp paprika breadcrumbs  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greek salad</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/greek-salad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/greek-salad/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Salad  4 tomatoes 1 cucumber 4 small red onions 20 dkg olives 125 g feta cheese  Dressing  4 tbsp olive oil 1.5 tsp lemon juice 1 tsp dried basil  Recipe Mix the dressing ingredients in a small bowl, chill in fridge for an hour.
Chop the tomatoes, cucumber and onions, mix them in a bowl.
Chop the feta into small cubes, mix it with the rest of the salad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pizza dough</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/pizza-dough/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/pizza-dough/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  153 grams 00 flour (1 cup plus 1 tablespoon) 153 grams all-purpose flour (1 cup plus 1 tablespoon and 2 teaspoons) 8 grams fine sea salt (1 teaspoon) 2 grams active dry yeast (¾ teaspoon) 4 grams extra-virgin olive oil (1 teaspoon)  Recipe Step 1 In a large mixing bowl, combine flours and salt.
Step 2 In a small mixing bowl, stir together 200 grams (a little less than 1 cup) lukewarm tap water, the yeast and the olive oil, then pour it into flour mixture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Potato salad with mayonaise</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/potato-salad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/potato-salad/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 kg potato 5 dl sour cream 3 red onions, chopped or finely sliced 2 dl mayonaise 1 tbsp mustard 0.5 tsp black pepper 0.5 tsp sugar juice of 0.5 lemon salt  Recipe Boil potatoes in salted water for 15-20 minutes.
Cut them into circles.
For the sauce, mix the mayo with the sour cream, mustard, salt, sugar, pepper and lemon juice.
Put the potatoes in a bowl, mix it with the onions and the sauce.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carrot cake</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/carrot-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 08:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/carrot-cake/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Cake  Nonstick vegetable oil spray 1 cup chopped walnuts 1 pound carrots, peeled, coarsely grated 1 cup buttermilk, room temperature 2½ cups all-purpose flour 2 teaspoons ground cinnamon 2 teaspoons ground ginger ½ teaspoon freshly grated nutmeg 2 teaspoons baking powder 1½ teaspoons kosher salt ¾ teaspoon baking soda 4 large eggs, room temperature 1 cup granulated sugar ¾ cup (packed) dark brown sugar 2 teaspoons vanilla extract ¾ cup vegetable oil  Frosting and assembly  12 ounces cream cheese, room temperature ¾ cup (1½ sticks) unsalted butter, room temperature 1 teaspoon vanilla extract Generous pinch of kosher salt 4 cups powdered sugar Candied Carrot Coins (optional)  Recipe Cake Step 1</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yoghurt cake</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/yoghurt-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 08:01:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/yoghurt-cake/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  Butter, for greasing the pan 4 large eggs, separated, at room temperature ½ cup/100 grams granulated sugar 3 tablespoons all-purpose flour 1⅔ cups/400 grams whole-milk Greek yogurt 1 lemon, zested and juiced Pinch of salt (optional)  Recipe Step 1
Heat oven to 350 degrees and butter an 8- or 9-inch springform pan.
Step 2
Using an electric hand mixer or a standing electric mixer fitted with the whisk attachment, beat egg whites on medium-low until the mixture looks frothy, 1 to 2 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicken Tikka Masala</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/chicken-tikka-masala/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 09:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/chicken-tikka-masala/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Chicken tikka  900 grams boneless, skinless chicken thighs 1 tablespoon kosher salt 1 tablespoon red chili powder 6 garlic cloves, peeled and mashed into a paste 1 (1-inch) piece ginger, peeled and mashed into a paste 2 lemons, juiced 1 cup|225 grams plain yogurt ¼ cup|60 ml canola oil 1 tablespoon garam masala 2 teaspoons ground turmeric 2 tablespoons unsalted butter, melted  Makhni gravy  1 pound|450 grams tomatoes, halved 1 garlic clove, peeled and mashed into a paste 1 (½-inch) piece ginger, peeled and mashed into a paste 1 teaspoon red chilli powder 1 small green chilli 1 cardamom pod 1 whole clove 15 grams cilantro with stems kosher salt, to taste ½ tablespoon unsalted butter ¼ cup|60ml heavy cream 2 tablespoons kasoori methi honey, to taste  Onion tomato masala  ¼ cup|60 ml canola oil ½ pound red onion, diced 2 garlic cloves, peeled and mashed into a paste 1 (¾-inch) piece ginger, peeled and mashed into a paste ½ teaspoon red chili powder ½ pound|225 grams tomatoes, diced ½ teaspoon garam masala kosher salt, to taste  Chicken tikka masala  3 tablespoons|150 grams ghee 3 teaspoons cumin seeds 8 whole dried red chiles 7 small garlic cloves, chopped 2 pounds|1 kg chicken tikka 2 teaspoons red chilli powder 1 ¼ cups onion tomato masala 1 ¼ cups makhni gravy 5 green chillies, thinly sliced ¼ cup|60 ml heavy cream 1 tablespoon unsalted butter 2 tablespoons kasoori methi 1 tablespoon garam masala kosher salt, to taste chopped cilantro, for garnish 1 (1-inch) piece ginger, peeled and julienned, for garnish steamed basmati rice, to serve  Directions Marinate the chicken: Place the chicken in a large bowl and toss with the salt, 1 teaspoon of the chili powder, half of the garlic paste, the lemon juice, and half of the ginger paste.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gnocchi</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/gnocchi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 06:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/gnocchi/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients (4 servings)  500g potatoes 130g flour 0.5 tsp salt 1 egg  Recipe Bake potatoes in oven for 1 hour, until very tender. Or boil in water. Mash potatoes with fork, masher, or potato ricer. Mix together with the flour, salt and egg, mix and knead until the dough is smooth and not sticky. Cut and shape, then boil in salted water until comes to surface, ~3 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brioche</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/brioche/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 06:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/brioche/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  T45 flour: 500g Salt: 9g Sugar: 70g Fresh yeast 15g Eggs: 150g (3 eggs) Milk: 150g Butter: 150g  Square pan: 27cm x 27cm
Recipe  Knead for 10 minutes without the butter Knead for 5 more minutes with the butter Pointing 30 min at room temperature and placing 12h at 4°c. Divide into 9 pieces Formatting Relaxation 10 min at 4°C Shaping, into 33cm snakes Braid them into 3 little loaves Primer: approximately 1h30min at 27°, in a turned off oven with a cup of hot water put under the pan Baking: 30 min at 150°C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pita bread</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/pita-bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 12:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/pita-bread/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 cups All purpose Flour plus 1/2 cup for dusting 1/2 cup Whole Wheat Flour 1 tbsp Sugar 1 tsp Salt 1 tbsp Olive OIl 2 tsp Yeast (refer notes) 1 cup Warm Water  Recipe Mix ingredients, need dough for 10 minutes.
Put in lightly oiled bowl, cover, and let proof for 2 hours.
Lightly deflate, and divide dough into 10 parts. Form into balls, cover with a kitchen towel, and let rest for 30 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Pesto</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/basic-pesto/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/basic-pesto/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 cups fresh basil leaves 2 tablespoons pine nuts or walnuts 2 large cloves garlic 0.5 cup olive oil 0.5 cup (45g) of grated parmesan  Preparation  Combine basil leaves, pine nuts or walnuts and garlic in a food processor and process until very finely minced. With the machine running slowly dribble in the oil and process until the mixture is smooth. Add the cheese and process very briefly, just long enough to combine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pogácsa</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/pogacsa/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/pogacsa/</guid>
      <description>60dkg liszt 25dkg túró 25dkg vaj 5dkg élesztő Annyi tejföl, hogy összeálljon a tészta 2 teáskanál só (sajt nélkül púpozott kanál, különben sótlan lesz) 1 tojás, sárgája a tésztába, fehérjével megkenni  Összegyúrni annyira, hogy összeáljon, letakarva kétszeresére keleszteni. Kinyújtani, 3-szor meghajtogatni, a hajtogatások között 10 perc szünetet tartani. Kinyújtjuk ujjnyi vastagra, megkenjük a tojásfehérjével, majd lisztbe mártott, apró pogácsaszaggatóval kiszaggatjuk. Előmelegített sütőben 200 fokon, 20 perc alatt pirosra sütjük.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Garlic knots</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/garlic-knots/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/garlic-knots/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Dough  1 package (2 1/4 teaspoons) active dry yeast 1 teaspoon sugar 7/8 cup (207ml) warm water (105�F to 115�F) 2 1/4 cups (300g) bread flour, plus more for flouring the work surface and your hands 1 teaspoon salt 1 tablespoon extra virgin olive oil, plus more for greasing the bowl and brushing the knots  Garlic butter 5 tablespoons unsalted butter 4 cloves garlic, minced 1/4 cup parsley, minced 1 teaspoon salt</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strudel</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/strudel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/strudel/</guid>
      <description>Crust (for 2 strudels)  250g butter 300g sugar Squeeze of one lemon One vanilla bean 500g flour (00 or AP) 1g salt 6g baking powder 40ml milk 100g eggs  Filling (for 1 strudel)  600g apples 50g sugar 50g toasted breadcrumbs Little butter 20g pine nuts Little cinnamon 25ml lemon juice  Crust is resting 30-60 minutes. Don&amp;rsquo;t have to knead a lot, knead a little before stretching.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classic Coleslaw</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/classic-coleslaw/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/classic-coleslaw/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  4 cups thinly sliced cabbage (green or purple, or a mix) 1 carrot, grated on the large holes of a box grater 2 green onions, thinly sliced on the diagonal 4 tablespoons mayonnaise 1 teaspoon yellow mustard 2 teaspoons cider vinegar or wine vinegar 1/8 teaspoon freshly ground black pepper, or more to taste Salt, to taste  Recipe Place the cabbage, carrot, and onions in a large bowl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jalfrezi curry</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/jalfrezi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/jalfrezi/</guid>
      <description>Chapati Ingredients  2 cups AP flour 3/4-1 cup warm water 1 tbsp olive oil  Jalfrezi curry Ingredients  Curry base gravy 2-3 chicken breasts, diced 2 tsp curry powder 2 tsp ground coriander 0.5 tsp ground chili 1 tsp garam masala 1 tsp ground cumin 1 tsp turmeric 1 pinch of fenugreek Egy large onion chopped Egy bell pepper chopped 2 cloves garlic crushed 1 small piece of ginger, grated 2 tbsp tomato puree Handful of fresh coriander Half a tomato, chopped  Recpie Chicken  Dice the chicken, season with salt, and cook it beforehand, in a little oil in a sillet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chop Suey</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/chop-suey/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/chop-suey/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  chicken breast or pork cut into small size -optional 1 cauliflower 1 piece carrot 8 pieces baby corn - optional 1 piece red bell pepper 1 piece green bell pepper ½ cabbage chopped 1 piece onion 4 cloves garlic crushed ¼ cup soy sauce 1 tablespoons oyster sauce - optional ¾ cup water 1 tablespoon cornstarch diluted in ½ cup water ¼ teaspoon ground black pepper 3 tablespoons cooking oil  Instructions  Heat oil in a wok or pan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lasagna</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/lasagna/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/lasagna/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Ragu  900g lb. ground pork 450g lb. ground beef chuck (20% fat) Kosher salt, freshly ground pepper 2 Tbsp. extra-virgin olive oil 56g pancetta or slab bacon, chopped 1 medium onion, finely chopped 1 celery stalk, finely chopped 1 medium carrot, peeled, finely chopped 6 garlic cloves, sliced 2 Tbsp. tomato paste 175ml dry white wine 1 800g can whole peeled tomatoes 236ml low-sodium chicken broth 236ml whole milk  Bechamel  100g unsalted butter 50g all-purpose flour 1400ml cups whole milk 110g Parmesan, coarsely grated (about 1 cup) Pinch of cayenne pepper Pinch of ground nutmeg Kosher salt, freshly ground pepper  Assembly  500g dried lasagna noodles Kosher salt Extra-virgin olive oil (for greasing)  Recipe RAGÙ BOLOGNESE Step 1 Preheat oven to 110° C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tortillas and Fajitas</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/tortillas-and-fajitas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/tortillas-and-fajitas/</guid>
      <description>Tortillas Ingredients (makes about a dozen tortillas, ~55g each)  450g AP flour 330ml warm water 4g salt (1 small teaspoon) 75g lard  or
 675g AP flour 495ml warm water 6g salt (1.5 small teaspoon) 100g lard  Recipe  Mix lard with flour, mix in salt Start mixing the warm water, don&amp;rsquo;t mix all of it in first. Add enough water so that sticky dough forms. Knead the dough for ~10 minutes, or until it&amp;rsquo;s smooth, supple, and is not sticky any more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple pie</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/apple-pie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/apple-pie/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Pie  3 pounds (1360g) good cooking apples such as Granny Smith, Jonagold, Golden Delicious, Fuji, or Braeburn (about 6 to 8 apples, depending on the size of your apples and the size of your pie dish) 1 tablespoon lemon juice or apple cider vinegar (to toss with the sliced apples so they don&amp;rsquo;t brown as you slice them) 1/2 cup to 2/3 cup sugar, depending on how sweet you like your pie 3 tablespoons all-purpose flour for thickening 1/2 teaspoon cinnamon 1/4 teaspoon ground allspice 1/4 teaspoon ground nutmeg 1 tablespoon brandy (Optional.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate chip cookie</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/chocolate-chip-cookie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/chocolate-chip-cookie/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1½ cups (200 g) all-purpose flour (spooning into measuring cups, then leveling) 1¼ tsp. (4 g) Diamond Crystal or ¾ tsp. (4 g) Morton kosher salt ¾ tsp. (4 g) baking soda ¾ cup (1½ sticks; 169 g) unsalted butter, divided 1 cup (200 g) (packed) dark brown sugar ¼ cup (50 g) granulated sugar 1 large egg 2 large egg yolks 2 tsp. vanilla extract 6 oz. (170 g) bittersweet chocolate (60%–70% cacao), coarsely chopped, or semisweet chocolate chips  Recipe Place racks in upper and lower thirds of oven; preheat to 375°.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fried Chicken Sandwich</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/fried-chicken-sandwich/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/fried-chicken-sandwich/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Chicken 1 tablespoon Diamond Crystal or 1¾ teaspoons Morton kosher salt
1 teaspoon light brown sugar
1 teaspoon baking powder
4 skin-on or skinless, boneless chicken thighs
Seasoned Mayonnaise 1 garlic clove, finely grated
2 tablespoons fresh lemon juice
½ cup mayonnaise
2 tablespoons finely chopped chives
½ teaspoon celery seeds
½ teaspoon freshly ground black pepper
Kosher salt
Assembly  1½ cups all-purpose flour ⅓ cup cornstarch 1 tablespoon garlic powder 1 tablespoon onion powder 1 tablespoon paprika 2 teaspoons cayenne pepper 2 tablespoons Diamond Crystal or 3½ teaspoons Morton kosher salt, plus more 1 large egg, beaten to blend 1 cup buttermilk 2 tablespoons bourbon (optional) 3 tablespoons hot sauce (such as Frank’s); plus more for serving (optional) Peanut or vegetable oil (for frying; about 8 cups) 4 seeded soft hamburger buns 3 tablespoons unsalted butter, melted Bread-and-Butter Pickles (for serving), plus 1 tablespoon brine 4 cups thinly sliced iceberg lettuce Freshly ground black pepper  Recipe Chicken Step 1 Mix salt, sugar, and baking powder in a small bowl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mashed Potatoes</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/mashed-potatoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/mashed-potatoes/</guid>
      <description> Cook the peeled, chopped potatoes (1.5kg) in salty water, 15-20 minutes. Mash the potatoes. Melt ~100g butter. Stir it into the potatoes. Heat up 1 cup of cream, and add aromatics (2-3 cloves of garlic) Stir the cream into the the potatoes in small batches.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Milk bread</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/milk-bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/milk-bread/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 packet of dry yeast (about 2 tsp.) 360 g bread flour 17 g (1.5 Tbsp.) sugar 7 g (0.5 Tbsp.) kosher salt 17 g (1 Tbsp. plus 0.5 tsp.) unsalted butter, room temperature, plus more for bowl  Recipe  Whisk yeast and 0.25 cup warm water (about 90°) in a small bowl. Let sit until foamy, about 5 minutes. Mix flour, sugar, and salt, and gradually add yeast mixture, and 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paneer Tikka Masala</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/paneer-tikka-masala/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/paneer-tikka-masala/</guid>
      <description>Tikka  2 tbsp yoghurt 1 tbsp chickpea flour 1 tsp paprika powder 1.5 tsp coriander powder 0.5 tsp masala powder 0.25 tsp turmeric powder less than 0.5 tsp salt   Mix everything well, then coat paneer, bell pepper and onion pieces well. Put it in the refrigerator for 20 minutes. Then roast them on oil or butter until they become golden brown.  Masala gravy  2 tbsp oil 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sinclair Potato Rolls</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/sinclair-potato-rolls/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/sinclair-potato-rolls/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients (makes 6 potato rolls)
 All-Purpose Flour, 290g Whole Milk, 100g Yukon Gold Potatoes, cooked and riced, 67g Potato Cooking Liquid, 24g Butter, 29g Eggs, 28g (half an egg) White Sugar, 24g Sea Salt, 7g Instant Yeast, 2g, or 5g Cake Yeast  Recipe  Mix dry ingredients Fold in the wet ingredients and mix, knead until dough forms. Let it rest covered in bowl for 20 minutes. Knead for a couple of minutes, form into ball, let it rise covered in bowl for 1 hour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sourdough bread</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/sourdough-bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/sourdough-bread/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  350 grams bread flour (preferably organic) 90 grams whole wheat flour (preferably organic and stone-ground) 350 grams 90°F/32°C filtered water 90 grams ripe sourdough starter (100% hydration) 9 grams kosher salt or fine sea salt white rice flour, for dusting  Example schedule Day one  8:30 AM – autolyse (mix flours and water). allow mixture to rest, covered, at 80°F/26°C for 1 hour, or as long as 2 hours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spicy Chicken Stir-Fry</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/spicy-chicken-stir-fry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/spicy-chicken-stir-fry/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 tsp. plus ¼ cup soy sauce 2½ tsp. cornstarch, divided 1½ tsp. sugar, divided ½ tsp. chilli powder (optional) ½ tsp. kosher salt, plus more 1 lb. skinless, boneless chicken thighs 1 tbsp. unseasoned rice vinegar 1 tbsp. oyster sauce 4 garlic cloves 1 2&amp;quot; piece ginger 1 bell pepper 1 onion 1 carrot 4 scallions ⅓ cup vegetable oil ¾ cup roasted, salted peanuts Rice (for serving; optional)  Recipe Whisk together 2 tsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Steak</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/steak/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/steak/</guid>
      <description>Season steak with salt and pepper, and let it sit at room temp for 30 minutes. Preheat the oven to 110 C, and bake the steak for around 45 minutes, or until the middle registers at 50 C. Heat 1 tbsp oil on high heat, and sear the steak on both sides for 2 minutes. Add 2-3 tbsp butter, 1 clove of garlic and a sprig of rosemary, and baste both sides for 90 seconds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/brioche-bun/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/brioche-bun/</guid>
      <description>FOR THE TANGZHONG: 9 grams (1 tablespoons) bread flour 30 ml whole milk 12 ml (2 tablespoons) water
FOR THE DOUGH: 90 ml whole milk, lukewarm 5 grams (1/2 tablespoon) active dry yeast 15 grams (1 tablespoons) sugar 207 grams bread flour 5 grams (1.5 teaspoons) kosher salt 0.5 large egg 0.5 egg yolk 20 grams (1.5 tablespoons) unsalted butter</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/spring-rolls/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/spring-rolls/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients
 1/4 cabbage, julienned 1 carrot, julienned 60g snow peas, julienned 60g wood ear mushrooms, finely chopped 2 spring onions, finely diced 1 tbsp peanut oil + more for frying 1/2 tsp salt 1/4 tsp MSG 1 tbsp soy sauce 1 tsp corn flour (mixed with 2 tbsp water) 10 spring roll wrappers Dipping sauce 2 tbsp fish sauce 20g palm sugar Juice of a lime 2 tbsp water small piece of ginger, grated 1 garlic clove, grated 2 birds eye chillies, finely sliced  Method</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cherry Biscuit Cobbler</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/cherry-biscuit-cobbler/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/cherry-biscuit-cobbler/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Biscuits  35g granulated sugar 3/4 Tbsp. baking powder 1.5 tsp. finely grated lemon zest 3/4 tsp. kosher salt 1.5 cups (200g) all-purpose flour, plus more for surface 85g chilled unsalted butter, cut into pieces 1 cup chilled heavy cream  Filling and Assembly  650g fresh (or frozen) sweet cherries, pitted 75g granulated sugar 50 ml fresh lemon juice 2 Tbsp. cornstarch 1/3 tsp. ground cinnamon 3/4 tsp. vanilla extract 1/5 tsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dinner rolls</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/dinner-rolls/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/dinner-rolls/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients For a 21 x 31 cm pan
Tangzhong  (25g) bread flour (33g) water (74g) whole milk  Dough  (393g) bread flour (11g) active dry yeast (instant works as well) 1 tsp (3.7g) fine sea salt (147g) whole milk (56g) granulated sugar (51g) unsalted butter, softened 1 whole egg, room temperature  Recipe  Make dough, let it rest and double in size, 1-2 hours Portion into 12 portions, arrange in pan, let it rise for 1-2 hours, until doubled Wash with egg wash, bake at 180C for 28-30 minutes  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Focaccia</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/focaccia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/focaccia/</guid>
      <description>Pan size: 22cmx32cm 425g flour 8g baker&amp;rsquo;s yeast. (1⅛ tsp active dry yeast) Pinch of sugar 0.5 tbsp kosher salt 2.5 tbsp olive oil  Combine flour with 1¼ cups (296 ml) room-temperature water, mix until incorporated and shaggy. Cover.
Stir yeast, sugar, and ¼ (60 ml) cup warm water in a small bowl. Let sit until yeast is foamy, about 5 minutes.
Pour yeast mixture into dough, mix on low speed until incorporated (~1 minute).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spaghetti and meatballs</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/spaghetti-and-meatballs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/spaghetti-and-meatballs/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Meatballs  500g ground beef and/or pork (80/20) 2 cloves garlic, minced 1/3 cup/30 g grated parmesan or pecorino 2 eggs 1 cups/100 g plain breadcrumbs 1/2 tsp salt black pepper  Sauce  2 small (2x400g) or 1 large (800g) cans peeled tomatoes 1 small onion, diced 1 tbsp tomato paste 1 bunch basil 2 cloves garlic, chopped 1 tsp salt 50ml olive oil  Recipe  Mix the meatball ingredients, form into small balls Sear the meatballs in batches in olive oil Sweat the onions in the same oil until translucent Add garlic, and fry for a couple of minutes more Salt everything Add tomato paste, and fry for a couple of minutes Add all the tomatoes Add a cup of water Add a tsp of salt, black pepper, and a bunch of basil stems Add the meatballs, and simmer for ~1 hour.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
