<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>italian on My Cookbook</title>
    <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/tags/italian/</link>
    <description>Recent content in italian on My Cookbook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 16:06:11 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/tags/italian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Pizza dough</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/pizza-dough/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/pizza-dough/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  153 grams 00 flour (1 cup plus 1 tablespoon) 153 grams all-purpose flour (1 cup plus 1 tablespoon and 2 teaspoons) 8 grams fine sea salt (1 teaspoon) 2 grams active dry yeast (¾ teaspoon) 4 grams extra-virgin olive oil (1 teaspoon)  Recipe Step 1 In a large mixing bowl, combine flours and salt.
Step 2 In a small mixing bowl, stir together 200 grams (a little less than 1 cup) lukewarm tap water, the yeast and the olive oil, then pour it into flour mixture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gnocchi</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/gnocchi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 06:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/gnocchi/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients (4 servings)  500g potatoes 130g flour 0.5 tsp salt 1 egg  Recipe Bake potatoes in oven for 1 hour, until very tender. Or boil in water. Mash potatoes with fork, masher, or potato ricer. Mix together with the flour, salt and egg, mix and knead until the dough is smooth and not sticky. Cut and shape, then boil in salted water until comes to surface, ~3 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lasagna</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/lasagna/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/lasagna/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Ragu  900g lb. ground pork 450g lb. ground beef chuck (20% fat) Kosher salt, freshly ground pepper 2 Tbsp. extra-virgin olive oil 56g pancetta or slab bacon, chopped 1 medium onion, finely chopped 1 celery stalk, finely chopped 1 medium carrot, peeled, finely chopped 6 garlic cloves, sliced 2 Tbsp. tomato paste 175ml dry white wine 1 800g can whole peeled tomatoes 236ml low-sodium chicken broth 236ml whole milk  Bechamel  100g unsalted butter 50g all-purpose flour 1400ml cups whole milk 110g Parmesan, coarsely grated (about 1 cup) Pinch of cayenne pepper Pinch of ground nutmeg Kosher salt, freshly ground pepper  Assembly  500g dried lasagna noodles Kosher salt Extra-virgin olive oil (for greasing)  Recipe RAGÙ BOLOGNESE Step 1 Preheat oven to 110° C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Pesto</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/basic-pesto/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/basic-pesto/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 cups fresh basil leaves 2 tablespoons pine nuts or walnuts 2 large cloves garlic 0.5 cup olive oil 0.5 cup of grated parmesan  Preparation  Combine basil leaves, pine nuts or walnuts and garlic in a food processor and process until very finely minced. With the machine running slowly dribble in the oil and process until the mixture is smooth. Add the cheese and process very briefly, just long enough to combine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Focaccia</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/focaccia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/focaccia/</guid>
      <description>Pan size: 22cmx32cm 425g flour 8g baker&amp;rsquo;s yeast. (1⅛ tsp active dry yeast) Pinch of sugar 0.5 tbsp kosher salt 2.5 tbsp olive oil  Combine flour with 1¼ cups (296 ml) room-temperature water, mix until incorporated and shaggy. Cover.
Stir yeast, sugar, and ¼ (60 ml) cup warm water in a small bowl. Let sit until yeast is foamy, about 5 minutes.
Pour yeast mixture into dough, mix on low speed until incorporated (~1 minute).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spaghetti and meatballs</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/spaghetti-and-meatballs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/spaghetti-and-meatballs/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Meatballs  500g ground beef and/or pork (80/20) 2 cloves garlic, minced 1/3 cup/30 g grated parmesan or pecorino 2 eggs 1 cups/100 g plain breadcrumbs 1/2 tsp salt black pepper  Sauce  2 small (2x400g) or 1 large (800g) cans peeled tomatoes 1 small onion, diced 1 tbsp tomato paste 1 bunch basil 2 cloves garlic, chopped 1 tsp salt 50ml olive oil  Recipe  Mix the meatball ingredients, form into small balls Sear the meatballs in batches in olive oil Sweat the onions in the same oil until translucent Add garlic, and fry for a couple of minutes more Salt everything Add tomato paste, and fry for a couple of minutes Add all the tomatoes Add a cup of water Add a tsp of salt, black pepper, and a bunch of basil stems Add the meatballs, and simmer for ~1 hour.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
