<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>italian on My Cookbook</title>
    <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/tags/italian/</link>
    <description>Recent content in italian on My Cookbook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 16:06:11 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/tags/italian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Carbonara</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/carbonara/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/carbonara/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  Salt 2 large eggs and 2 large yolks, room temperature 30g grated pecorino Romano, plus additional for serving 30g grated Parmesan Coarsely ground black pepper 1 tablespoon olive oil 100g guanciale, pancetta or bacon, sliced into pieces about ¼ inch thick by ⅓ inch square 340g spaghetti (about ¾ box)  Recipe Place a large pot of lightly salted water (no more than 1 tablespoon salt) over high heat, and bring to a boil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pasta alla Norma</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/pasta-alla-norma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/pasta-alla-norma/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1½ pounds eggplant Olive oil as needed (at least ½ cup) Salt and pepper 1 tablespoon chopped garlic 3 or 4 dried chiles 1½ pounds tomatoes, chopped (canned are fine; about 1 can) 1 teaspoon good dried oregano, or 1 tablespoon fresh 1 pound long pasta ½ cup chopped parsley or basil ½ cup grated ricotta salata (or in a pinch, pecorino Romano)  Recipe Step 1
Slice the eggplant about ½ inch thick.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spaghetti Puttanesca</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/spaghetti-puttanesca/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/spaghetti-puttanesca/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 /4 cup extra-virgin olive oil 4 large garlic cloves, finely chopped 1 28.2-ounce can peeled tomatoes in puree with basil 1/2 cup Kalamata olives, halved, pitted 3 anchovy fillets, chopped 1 1/2 tablespoons drained capers 1 teaspoon dried oregano 1/2 teaspoon dried crushed red pepper 3/4 pound spaghetti 2 tablespoons chopped fresh Italian parsley Grated Parmesan cheese  Recipe Step 1
Heat oil in large pot over medium heat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eggplant parmesan</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/eggplant-parmesan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/eggplant-parmesan/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1kg eggplant 1 tsp salt, plus more to taste 1/4 cup plus 1 tablespoon extra virgin olive oil, divided, plus more to oil the sheet pans 2 cloves garlic, minced 2 (28-ounce or 800g) cans whole peeled tomatoes (preferably San Marzano) diced, reserving the juices, or crushed tomatoes 1/2 cup finely chopped fresh basil, packed Kosher salt Freshly ground black pepper, to taste 1 1/2 to 2 cups breadcrumbs 1 1/4 cups shredded Parmesan cheese, divided 1 cup all-purpose flour 4 large eggs, beaten (more if needed) 700g pounds fresh mozzarella cheese, sliced into 1/4-inch slices  23cm x 33cm casserole</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bolognese sauce</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/bolognese/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/bolognese/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 medium onion, chopped 1 celery stalk, chopped 1 small carrot, peeled, chopped 3 Tbsp. extra-virgin olive oil 1 lb. ground beef chuck (20% fat), patted dry Kosher salt 3 oz. thinly sliced pancetta, finely chopped 1 cup dry white wine ⅓ cup tomato paste 1 bay leaf Pinch of finely grated nutmeg 2 cups (or more) homemade chicken stock or low-sodium chicken broth 1 cup whole milk 1 lb.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pizza dough</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/pizza-dough/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/pizza-dough/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  153 grams 00 flour (1 cup plus 1 tablespoon) 153 grams all-purpose flour (1 cup plus 1 tablespoon and 2 teaspoons) 8 grams fine sea salt (1 teaspoon) 2 grams active dry yeast (¾ teaspoon) 4 grams extra-virgin olive oil (1 teaspoon)  Recipe Step 1 In a large mixing bowl, combine flours and salt.
Step 2 In a small mixing bowl, stir together 200 grams (a little less than 1 cup) lukewarm tap water, the yeast and the olive oil, then pour it into flour mixture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gnocchi</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/gnocchi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 06:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/gnocchi/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients (4 servings)  500g potatoes 130g flour 0.5 tsp salt 1 egg  Recipe Bake potatoes in oven for 1 hour, until very tender. Or boil in water. Mash potatoes with fork, masher, or potato ricer. Mix together with the flour, salt and egg, mix and knead until the dough is smooth and not sticky. Cut and shape, then boil in salted water until comes to surface, ~3 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Pesto</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/basic-pesto/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/basic-pesto/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 cups fresh basil leaves 2 tablespoons pine nuts or walnuts 2 large cloves garlic 0.5 cup olive oil 0.5 cup (45g) of grated parmesan  Preparation  Combine basil leaves, pine nuts or walnuts and garlic in a food processor and process until very finely minced. With the machine running slowly dribble in the oil and process until the mixture is smooth. Add the cheese and process very briefly, just long enough to combine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lasagna</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/lasagna/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/lasagna/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Ragu  900g lb. ground pork 450g lb. ground beef chuck (20% fat) Kosher salt, freshly ground pepper 2 Tbsp. extra-virgin olive oil 56g pancetta or slab bacon, chopped 1 medium onion, finely chopped 1 celery stalk, finely chopped 1 medium carrot, peeled, finely chopped 6 garlic cloves, sliced 2 Tbsp. tomato paste 175ml dry white wine 1 800g can whole peeled tomatoes 236ml low-sodium chicken broth 236ml whole milk  Bechamel  100g unsalted butter 50g all-purpose flour 1400ml cups whole milk 110g Parmesan, coarsely grated (about 1 cup) Pinch of cayenne pepper Pinch of ground nutmeg Kosher salt, freshly ground pepper  Assembly  500g dried lasagna noodles Kosher salt Extra-virgin olive oil (for greasing)  Recipe RAGÙ BOLOGNESE Step 1 Preheat oven to 110° C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Focaccia</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/focaccia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/focaccia/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients
 420ml water 15g fresh yeast 1 tsp honey 1 tbsp olive oil 2 tsp salt 500g flour  Recipe
 Mix ingredients, cover, rest for 10 min Fold, rest for 10 min Fold, rest for 10 min Fold, rest for 10 min Place in bowl, cover with some olive oil Rest in fridge overnight Remove from fridge. Cover pan with baking paper and add olive oil. Fold dough and spread in tray.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spaghetti and meatballs</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/spaghetti-and-meatballs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/spaghetti-and-meatballs/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Meatballs  500g ground beef and/or pork (80/20) 2 cloves garlic, minced 1/3 cup/30 g grated parmesan or pecorino 2 eggs 1 cups/100 g plain breadcrumbs 1/2 tsp salt black pepper  Sauce  2 small (2x400g) or 1 large (800g) cans peeled tomatoes 1 small onion, diced 1 tbsp tomato paste 1 bunch basil 2 cloves garlic, chopped 1 tsp salt 50ml olive oil  Recipe  Mix the meatball ingredients, form into small balls Sear the meatballs in batches in olive oil Sweat the onions in the same oil until translucent Add garlic, and fry for a couple of minutes more Salt everything Add tomato paste, and fry for a couple of minutes Add all the tomatoes Add a cup of water Add a tsp of salt, black pepper, and a bunch of basil stems Add the meatballs, and simmer for ~1 hour.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
