<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>vegetarian on My Cookbook</title>
    <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/tags/vegetarian/</link>
    <description>Recent content in vegetarian on My Cookbook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 16:06:11 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/tags/vegetarian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Eggplant parmesan</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/eggplant-parmesan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/eggplant-parmesan/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1kg eggplant 1 tsp salt, plus more to taste 1/4 cup plus 1 tablespoon extra virgin olive oil, divided, plus more to oil the sheet pans 2 cloves garlic, minced 2 (28-ounce or 800g) cans whole peeled tomatoes (preferably San Marzano) diced, reserving the juices, or crushed tomatoes 1/2 cup finely chopped fresh basil, packed Kosher salt Freshly ground black pepper, to taste 1 1/2 to 2 cups breadcrumbs 1 1/4 cups shredded Parmesan cheese, divided 1 cup all-purpose flour 4 large eggs, beaten (more if needed) 700g pounds fresh mozzarella cheese, sliced into 1/4-inch slices  23cm x 33cm casserole</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chop Suey</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/chop-suey/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/chop-suey/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  chicken breast or pork cut into small size -optional 1 cauliflower 1 piece carrot 8 pieces baby corn - optional 1 piece red bell pepper 1 piece green bell pepper ½ cabbage chopped 1 piece onion 4 cloves garlic crushed ¼ cup soy sauce 1 tablespoons oyster sauce - optional ¾ cup water 1 tablespoon cornstarch diluted in ½ cup water ¼ teaspoon ground black pepper 3 tablespoons cooking oil  Instructions  Heat oil in a wok or pan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paneer Tikka Masala</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/paneer-tikka-masala/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/paneer-tikka-masala/</guid>
      <description>Tikka  2 tbsp yoghurt 1 tbsp chickpea flour 1 tsp paprika powder 1.5 tsp coriander powder 0.5 tsp masala powder 0.25 tsp turmeric powder less than 0.5 tsp salt   Mix everything well, then coat paneer, bell pepper and onion pieces well. Put it in the refrigerator for 20 minutes. Then roast them on oil or butter until they become golden brown.  Masala gravy  2 tbsp oil 0.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
