<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>vegetarian on My Cookbook</title>
    <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/tags/vegetarian/</link>
    <description>Recent content in vegetarian on My Cookbook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 16:06:11 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/tags/vegetarian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Lentil stew (lencsefőzelék)</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/lentil-stew/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/lentil-stew/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients 250g lentils 1 onion 2 cloves garlic 1 tbsp oil 1 tsp paprika 1l water 2 bay leaves salt 200ml sour cream 1 tbsp flour 1 tbsp mustard
Recipe Wash lentils, soak in water for 1-2 hours. Finely chop the onion, fry in a pot, add garlic. Add paprika, and pour in the water. Drain the lentils and add them to the pot. Add water to cover the lentil. Simmer until lentils are softened.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aloo gobi</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/aloo-gobi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/aloo-gobi/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 medium russet potatoes, cut into 2&amp;quot;-long sticks 1 medium head of cauliflower, cut into small florets 5 Tbsp. extra-virgin olive oil, divided 1 tsp. cumin seeds ½ tsp. ground turmeric 1 small onion, finely chopped 1 Tbsp. thinly sliced ginger Pinch of asafetida (optional, but really great) Pinch of red chili powder 1 tsp. (or more) kosher salt 1 Tbsp. (or more) fresh lime juice ½ cup chopped cilantro leaves with tender stems  Recipe Step 1 Preheat oven to 400°.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chinese stir-fried green beans</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/chinese-stir-fried-green-beans/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 14:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/chinese-stir-fried-green-beans/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  400g green beans 2 tsp oil 1 tbsp dark soy sauce 1 tbsp cooking wine 2 tsp minced garlic 2 tsp grated ginger 1/2 tsp sugar 1/2 tsp sesame oil 1/4 tsp salt 1/4 tsp red pepper flakes (optional) Garnish: sesame seeds  Recipe Combine sauce ingredients.
Dry-fry beans in a little oil for 10 minutes, until tender crisp and charred.
Pour sauce into skillet, sauté for a couple of minutes until thickened and the beans are coated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pumpkin cream soup</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/pumpkin-cream-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/pumpkin-cream-soup/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2kg pumpkins 4 tablespoons butter 2 cups medium yellow onions, chopped, about 2 cups 3 clove garlic cloves, minced 2 to 3 teaspoons smoked paprika, more or less to taste 1/2 teaspoon ground cumin 1 pinch cayenne pepper 1 large tart green apple peeled, cored, chopped (about 2 cups) 4 cups chicken broth 1 cup water 1 teaspoon fresh thyme or 1/2 teaspoon dried thyme 1/4 teaspoon ground sage 1 cup milk 1/2 cup cream Kosher salt and freshly ground black pepper, to taste Handful of toasted pepitas (shelled pumpkin seeds) for garnish  Recipe Bake pumpkin at 180 C for 45-60 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pasta alla Norma</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/pasta-alla-norma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/pasta-alla-norma/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1½ pounds eggplant Olive oil as needed (at least ½ cup) Salt and pepper 1 tablespoon chopped garlic 3 or 4 dried chiles 1½ pounds tomatoes, chopped (canned are fine; about 1 can) 1 teaspoon good dried oregano, or 1 tablespoon fresh 1 pound long pasta ½ cup chopped parsley or basil ½ cup grated ricotta salata (or in a pinch, pecorino Romano)  Recipe Step 1
Slice the eggplant about ½ inch thick.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spaghetti Puttanesca</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/spaghetti-puttanesca/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/spaghetti-puttanesca/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 /4 cup extra-virgin olive oil 4 large garlic cloves, finely chopped 1 28.2-ounce can peeled tomatoes in puree with basil 1/2 cup Kalamata olives, halved, pitted 3 anchovy fillets, chopped 1 1/2 tablespoons drained capers 1 teaspoon dried oregano 1/2 teaspoon dried crushed red pepper 3/4 pound spaghetti 2 tablespoons chopped fresh Italian parsley Grated Parmesan cheese  Recipe Step 1
Heat oil in large pot over medium heat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Green bean casserole</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/green-bean-casserole/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2023 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/green-bean-casserole/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients (8 servings)
 1kg green beans Kosher salt 2 Tbsp. extra-virgin olive oil, divided 1 lb. crimini mushrooms, sliced, divided 6 Tbsp. unsalted butter, divided 4 large sprigs thyme, divided 2 Tbsp. all-purpose flour 300ml cups whole milk 240ml cup heavy cream 4 garlic cloves, finely grated ½ cup grated Parmesan Freshly ground black pepper ¾ cup French’s fried onions  Recipe  Preheat oven to 190 C Cook beans to half tender in salted water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eggplant parmesan</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/eggplant-parmesan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/eggplant-parmesan/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1kg eggplant 1 tsp salt, plus more to taste 1/4 cup plus 1 tablespoon extra virgin olive oil, divided, plus more to oil the sheet pans 2 cloves garlic, minced 2 (28-ounce or 800g) cans whole peeled tomatoes (preferably San Marzano) diced, reserving the juices, or crushed tomatoes 1/2 cup finely chopped fresh basil, packed Kosher salt Freshly ground black pepper, to taste 1 1/2 to 2 cups breadcrumbs 1 1/4 cups shredded Parmesan cheese, divided 1 cup all-purpose flour 4 large eggs, beaten (more if needed) 700g pounds fresh mozzarella cheese, sliced into 1/4-inch slices  23cm x 33cm casserole</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baba Ganoush (eggplant dip)</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/baba-ganoush/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2023 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/baba-ganoush/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 to 2 globe eggplants (totaling 2 pounds or 900g) 3 tablespoons extra virgin olive oil 2 to 3 tablespoons roasted tahini (sesame paste) 1 to 2 garlic cloves (more or less depending on how garlicky you want your baba ghanoush to be), finely chopped 1/2 teaspoon ground cumin Juice of 1 lemon (about 2 1/2 tablespoons) Salt and cayenne pepper to taste 1 tablespoon chopped parsley  Recipe Cut eggplants in half, poke them with a fork.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chop Suey</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/chop-suey/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/chop-suey/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  chicken breast or pork cut into small size -optional 1 cauliflower 1 piece carrot 8 pieces baby corn - optional 1 piece red bell pepper 1 piece green bell pepper ½ cabbage chopped 1 piece onion 4 cloves garlic crushed ¼ cup soy sauce 1 tablespoons oyster sauce - optional ¾ cup water 1 tablespoon cornstarch diluted in ½ cup water ¼ teaspoon ground black pepper 3 tablespoons cooking oil  Instructions  Heat oil in a wok or pan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paneer Tikka Masala</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/paneer-tikka-masala/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/paneer-tikka-masala/</guid>
      <description>Tikka  2 tbsp yoghurt 1 tbsp chickpea flour 1 tsp paprika powder 1.5 tsp coriander powder 0.5 tsp masala powder 0.25 tsp turmeric powder less than 0.5 tsp salt   Mix everything well, then coat paneer, bell pepper and onion pieces well. Put it in the refrigerator for 20 minutes. Then roast them on oil or butter until they become golden brown.  Masala gravy  2 tbsp oil 0.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
