<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>indian on My Cookbook</title>
    <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/tags/indian/</link>
    <description>Recent content in indian on My Cookbook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 16:06:11 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/tags/indian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Aloo gobi</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/aloo-gobi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/aloo-gobi/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 medium russet potatoes, cut into 2&amp;quot;-long sticks 1 medium head of cauliflower, cut into small florets 5 Tbsp. extra-virgin olive oil, divided 1 tsp. cumin seeds ½ tsp. ground turmeric 1 small onion, finely chopped 1 Tbsp. thinly sliced ginger Pinch of asafetida (optional, but really great) Pinch of red chili powder 1 tsp. (or more) kosher salt 1 Tbsp. (or more) fresh lime juice ½ cup chopped cilantro leaves with tender stems  Recipe Step 1 Preheat oven to 400°.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicken Tikka Masala</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/chicken-tikka-masala/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 09:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/chicken-tikka-masala/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Chicken tikka  900 grams boneless, skinless chicken thighs 1 tablespoon kosher salt 1 tablespoon red chili powder 6 garlic cloves, peeled and mashed into a paste 1 (1-inch) piece ginger, peeled and mashed into a paste 2 lemons, juiced 1 cup|225 grams plain yogurt ¼ cup|60 ml canola oil 1 tablespoon garam masala 2 teaspoons ground turmeric 2 tablespoons unsalted butter, melted  Makhni gravy  1 pound|450 grams tomatoes, halved 1 garlic clove, peeled and mashed into a paste 1 (½-inch) piece ginger, peeled and mashed into a paste 1 teaspoon red chilli powder 1 small green chilli 1 cardamom pod 1 whole clove 15 grams cilantro with stems kosher salt, to taste ½ tablespoon unsalted butter ¼ cup|60ml heavy cream 2 tablespoons kasoori methi honey, to taste  Onion tomato masala  ¼ cup|60 ml canola oil ½ pound red onion, diced 2 garlic cloves, peeled and mashed into a paste 1 (¾-inch) piece ginger, peeled and mashed into a paste ½ teaspoon red chili powder ½ pound|225 grams tomatoes, diced ½ teaspoon garam masala kosher salt, to taste  Chicken tikka masala  3 tablespoons|150 grams ghee 3 teaspoons cumin seeds 8 whole dried red chiles 7 small garlic cloves, chopped 2 pounds|1 kg chicken tikka 2 teaspoons red chilli powder 1 ¼ cups onion tomato masala 1 ¼ cups makhni gravy 5 green chillies, thinly sliced ¼ cup|60 ml heavy cream 1 tablespoon unsalted butter 2 tablespoons kasoori methi 1 tablespoon garam masala kosher salt, to taste chopped cilantro, for garnish 1 (1-inch) piece ginger, peeled and julienned, for garnish steamed basmati rice, to serve  Directions Marinate the chicken: Place the chicken in a large bowl and toss with the salt, 1 teaspoon of the chili powder, half of the garlic paste, the lemon juice, and half of the ginger paste.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jalfrezi curry</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/jalfrezi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/jalfrezi/</guid>
      <description>Chapati Ingredients  2 cups AP flour 3/4-1 cup warm water 1 tbsp olive oil  Jalfrezi curry Ingredients  Curry base gravy 2-3 chicken breasts, diced 2 tsp curry powder 2 tsp ground coriander 0.5 tsp ground chili 1 tsp garam masala 1 tsp ground cumin 1 tsp turmeric 1 pinch of fenugreek Egy large onion chopped Egy bell pepper chopped 2 cloves garlic crushed 1 small piece of ginger, grated 2 tbsp tomato puree Handful of fresh coriander Half a tomato, chopped  Recpie Chicken  Dice the chicken, season with salt, and cook it beforehand, in a little oil in a sillet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paneer Tikka Masala</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/paneer-tikka-masala/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/paneer-tikka-masala/</guid>
      <description>Tikka  2 tbsp yoghurt 1 tbsp chickpea flour 1 tsp paprika powder 1.5 tsp coriander powder 0.5 tsp masala powder 0.25 tsp turmeric powder less than 0.5 tsp salt   Mix everything well, then coat paneer, bell pepper and onion pieces well. Put it in the refrigerator for 20 minutes. Then roast them on oil or butter until they become golden brown.  Masala gravy  2 tbsp oil 0.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
