<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>side on My Cookbook</title>
    <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/tags/side/</link>
    <description>Recent content in side on My Cookbook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 14:06:11 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/tags/side/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chinese stir-fried green beans</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/chinese-stir-fried-green-beans/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 14:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/chinese-stir-fried-green-beans/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  400g green beans 2 tsp oil 1 tbsp dark soy sauce 1 tbsp cooking wine 2 tsp minced garlic 2 tsp grated ginger 1/2 tsp sugar 1/2 tsp sesame oil 1/4 tsp salt 1/4 tsp red pepper flakes (optional) Garnish: sesame seeds  Recipe Combine sauce ingredients.
Dry-fry beans in a little oil for 10 minutes, until tender crisp and charred.
Pour sauce into skillet, sauté for a couple of minutes until thickened and the beans are coated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Green bean casserole</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/green-bean-casserole/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2023 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/green-bean-casserole/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients (8 servings)
 1kg green beans Kosher salt 2 Tbsp. extra-virgin olive oil, divided 1 lb. crimini mushrooms, sliced, divided 6 Tbsp. unsalted butter, divided 4 large sprigs thyme, divided 2 Tbsp. all-purpose flour 300ml cups whole milk 240ml cup heavy cream 4 garlic cloves, finely grated ½ cup grated Parmesan Freshly ground black pepper ¾ cup French’s fried onions  Recipe  Preheat oven to 190 C Cook beans to half tender in salted water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classic Coleslaw</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/classic-coleslaw/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/classic-coleslaw/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  4 cups thinly sliced cabbage (green or purple, or a mix) 1 carrot, grated on the large holes of a box grater 2 green onions, thinly sliced on the diagonal 4 tablespoons mayonnaise 1 teaspoon yellow mustard 2 teaspoons cider vinegar or wine vinegar 1/8 teaspoon freshly ground black pepper, or more to taste Salt, to taste  Recipe Place the cabbage, carrot, and onions in a large bowl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mashed Potatoes</title>
      <link>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/mashed-potatoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 16:06:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markvincze.github.io/cookbook/post/mashed-potatoes/</guid>
      <description> Cook the peeled, chopped potatoes (1.5kg) in salty water, 15-20 minutes. Mash the potatoes. Melt ~100g butter. Stir it into the potatoes. Heat up 1 cup of cream, and add aromatics (2-3 cloves of garlic) Stir the cream into the the potatoes in small batches.  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
